<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shori Takaoka | Chaochen Wang - Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/shori-takaoka/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/shori-takaoka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Shori Takaoka</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2025 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Shori Takaoka</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/shori-takaoka/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment selection and influencing factors for chronic lymphocytic leukemia: a physician survey in Japan</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2024cllsurvey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2024cllsurvey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;: Chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) is a rare form of lymphoma in Japan. This study aimed to explore hematologists&amp;rsquo; motivations and considerations in making treatment decisions for CLL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;: Responses from hematologists treating CLL, obtained through an online survey, were descriptively analyzed. Subgroup analyses by preferred first-line (1L) treatment, years of clinical experience, and level of interest in CLL were conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;: Out of 107 hematologists surveyed, 82.2% identified Bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitors (BTKi) as their primary choice for 1L treatment; the reasons included established clinical evidence (61.4%) and oral administration convenience (56.8%). Key factors influencing 1L treatment selection among those favoring BTKi included the presence of 17p deletion, TP53 mutation, and patient&amp;rsquo;s fitness status. BTKi was favored by 92.6% of hematologists with &amp;lt; 10 years of clinical experience and by 78.8% with more experience. The main reasons for choosing BTKi included safety (50.0%) and tolerance (46.7%) among hematologists who stated they had a specific interest in CLL and the oral administration route (62.1%) among hematologists with lower interest. When BTKi was used as 1L therapy, venetoclax-based regimens were preferred for second-line treatment. The most common concern about BTKi was substantial out-of-pocket costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;: Although many Japanese hematologists select their treatment based on clinical evidence, variations exist in treatment strategies, possibly associated with hematologists&amp;rsquo; experience and interest in CLL. These findings underscore the importance of further promoting evidence-based treatments to ensure that all physicians can make informed decisions. Future research should explore additional factors that influence CLL treatment decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: Chronic lymphocytic leukemia; Online survey; Treatment selection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
