<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Liane Gillespie-Akar | Chaochen Wang - Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/liane-gillespie-akar/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/liane-gillespie-akar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Liane Gillespie-Akar</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2024 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Liane Gillespie-Akar</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/liane-gillespie-akar/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bowel Urgency in Patients with Ulcerative Colitis and Crohn’s Disease: A Cross-Sectional Real-World Survey in Japan</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/adelphiuccd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/adelphiuccd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: Bowel urgency (BU) is among the most disruptive of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) symptoms. However, data on its prevalence and association with disease activity are limited. This real-world study of Japanese patients with IBD evaluated BU prevalence and compared clinical outcomes and health-related quality of life (HRQoL) between patients with and without BU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Data were drawn from the Adelphi IBD Disease Specific Programme™, a cross-sectional survey of physicians and their patients with ulcerative colitis (UC) and Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease (CD). Physicians reported demographic and clinical data, including disease activity measures (Mayo score and CD Activity Index [CDAI]), for consulting patients, who voluntarily completed a patient-reported questionnaire, including HRQoL measures (Short IBD Questionnaire [SIBDQ] and EQ-5D-5L). Outcomes were compared between patients with and without BU using t-, Fisher exact and Mann-Whitney U tests as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;:  Of 120 UC patients, 27.5% (n = 33) self-reported BU; physicians were unaware of BU in 54.5% (n = 18) of these patients. Patients with BU had higher mean Mayo scores (p &amp;lt; 0.01) and lower mean SIBDQ scores (47.9 vs 56.6, p &amp;lt; 0.01) than patients without BU, with mean EQ-5D-5L scores 0.83 and 0.87, respectively (p = 0.06). Physicians were satisfied with treatment but believed better control could be achieved for 39.4% of patients with BU and 35.6% without. Of 114 CD patients, 17.5% (n = 20) self-reported BU; physicians were unaware of BU in 75.0% (n = 15) of these patients. Patients with BU had higher mean CDAI scores (p &amp;lt; 0.01) and lower mean SIBDQ (48.7 vs 56.2, p &amp;lt; 0.01) and EQ-5D-5L scores (0.81 vs 0.88, p &amp;lt; 0.01) than patients without BU. Physicians were satisfied but believed better control could be achieved for 40.0% of patients with BU vs 19.1% without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;: Patients with BU have worse clinical outcomes and HRQoL than patients without, underlining the need for improved physician-patient communication regarding BU and new IBD therapeutic options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: Bowel urgency; Crohn’s disease; Disease burden; IBD; Japan; Real-world; Survey; Ulcerative colitis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
