<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Keiko Wada | Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>/authors/keiko-wada/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/keiko-wada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Keiko Wada</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2020 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Keiko Wada</title>
      <link>/authors/keiko-wada/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association between parental history of diabetes and the incidence of type 2 diabetes mellitus differs according to the sex of the parent and offspring’s body weight: A finding from a Japanese worksite-based cohort study</title>
      <link>/publication/journal-article/fhdm2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/journal-article/fhdm2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To investigate differences in the association of parental history of diabetes with the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in the offspring according to the sex of the parent and the offspring&amp;rsquo;s body weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A prospective cohort study of 4446 middle-aged non-diabetic Japanese men and women were followed in Aichi Prefecture, central Japan, from 2002 to 2011. Subjects were categorized by their self-reported parental history of diabetes (&amp;ldquo;no parental history,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;father only,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;mother only,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;both&amp;rdquo;). The association of parental history of diabetes and incidence in the offspring was examined according to overweight status adjusted for age, sex, birth weight, smoking, alcohol consumption, physical activity, total energy intake, body mass index, and number of metabolic syndrome components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During follow-up (median 8.9 years), 277 subjects developed T2DM. Parental history of diabetes was positively associated with T2DM incidence. However, stratified analysis by overweight status revealed that only maternal history was associated with increased T2DM incidence in non-overweight subjects (hazard ratio=2.35, 95% confidence interval: 1.41-3.91). While in overweight subjects, paternal history was significantly associated with higher T2DM incidence (hazard ratio=1.98, 95% confidence interval: 1.19-3.28).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results suggest that parental history of diabetes mellitus is associated with the incidence of T2DM in offspring differently according to the sex of the affected parent and the offspring&amp;rsquo;s body weight.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive association between high‐sensitivity C‐reactive protein and incidence of type 2 diabetes mellitus in Japanese workers: 6‐year follow‐up</title>
      <link>/publication/journal-article/crpdm2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/journal-article/crpdm2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elevated high-sensitivity C-reactive protein (hs-CRP), a marker of low-grade systemic inflammation, may be involved in the etiology of type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). However, whether inflammation precedes development of T2DM independent of cigarette smoking and obesity remains to be confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We studied 4213 civil servants in a local government in Japan aged 35-66 years at baseline in 2002, who donated blood samples and were followed 6 years. Hazard ratios (HR) of T2DM according to the hs-CRP quartiles [range Q1: 0.02-0.18 (reference), Q2: 0.18-0.33, Q3: 0.33-0.67 and Q4: 0.67-9.62 mg/L) were estimated by Cox proportional hazards model adjusted for gender, age, body mass index, alcohol intake, smoking status (current, past and never), number of cigarettes per day, physical activity, family history of diabetes (Model 1) and variables in Model 1 + glucose (Model 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The geometric mean [95% confidence interval (CI)] of hs-CRP was 0.36 mg/L (0.34-0.37). During the follow-up, 156 new T2DM cases were confirmed. In total sample, Model 2 HRs (95% CIs) for hs-CRP quartiles Q2-Q4 compared with Q1 were 0.69 (0.36-1.26), 1.47 (0.91-2.39) and 1.78 (1.10-2.88), respectively (p for linear trend = 0.014). Stratified analysis revealed that a statistically significant association was observed only in normal weight non-current smokers with Model 2 HRs (CIs) being 0.79 (0.29-2.17), 2.63 (1.25-5.56) and 3.19 (1.49-6.86) for Q2-Q4 compared with Q1, respectively (p for linear trend = 0.0006). The relationship did not change materially after further adjusting for log-homeostasis model assessment or exclusion of past smokers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings imply that higher hs-CRP itself or existence of chronic systemic inflammation precedes onset of T2DM independent of obesity and smoking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
