<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>8 on Be ambitious</title>
    <link>https://winterwang.github.io/publication_types/8/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 8 on Be ambitious</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2019 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://winterwang.github.io/publication_types/8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Esophageal cancer in high-risk areas of China: research progress and challenges</title>
      <link>https://winterwang.github.io/publication/esophageal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://winterwang.github.io/publication/esophageal/</guid>
      <description>Abstract PURPOSE: The extremely high incidence of esophageal cancer in certain rural areas of China has prompted significant intellectual curiosity and research efforts both in China and abroad.
METHODS: We summarize the research progress over the past several decades in high-risk areas (Linxian, Cixian, Shexian, and Yanting) based on literature research and our field trip (2012-2013).
RESULTS: Considerable progress in clarifying the environmental risk factors and pathogenesis of esophageal cancer in high-risk areas has been achieved over the past several decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Trend in Overweight and Obesity and Its Association With Cardiovascular Disease Incidence</title>
      <link>https://winterwang.github.io/publication/globalobesity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://winterwang.github.io/publication/globalobesity/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Although the global prevalence of both the overweight and obese is on the rise, there are variations among regions or countries, and sexes. Approximately half or more than half of the population are overweight/obese defined as body mass index $\geqslant$ 25 $kg/m^2$in the Americas (61.1%), Europe (54.8%), and Eastern Mediterranean (46.0%) according to the World Health Organization, while a much lower prevalence is observed in Africa (26.9%), South-East Asia (13.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>