<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yumi Sugawara | Chaochen Wang - Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/yumi-sugawara/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/yumi-sugawara/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Yumi Sugawara</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2021 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Yumi Sugawara</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/yumi-sugawara/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-intensity cigarette smoking and mortality risks: a pooled analysis of prospective cohort studies in Japan</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2021lowintensity_pool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2021lowintensity_pool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: Increasing proportions of smokers in Japan smoke less than 10 cigarettes per day (CPD). Yet, the health risks of low-intensity smoking in Asia are poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: We performed a pooled analysis of 410,294 adults from nine population-based prospective cohort studies participating in the Japan Cohort Consortium. Cigarette use data were collected at each study baseline in 1983-1994. Study specific hazard ratios (HRs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs) for all-cause and cause-specific mortality were calculated using multivariable-adjusted Cox regression by CPD among current smokers and by age at cessation among former smokers with never smokers as the referent group. Pooled HRs and CIs were computed using a random effect model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: The smoking prevalence was 54.5% in men and 7.4% in women. About 15.5% of male and 50.4% of female current smokers smoked 1-10 CPD (low-intensity). Both male and female low-intensity smokers had higher all-cause mortality risks than never smokers. Risks were further higher with increasing CPD in a dose-response manner. HRs (95% CIs) were 1.27 (0.97-1.66), 1.45 (1.33-1.59), and 1.49 (1.38-1.62) for 1-2, 3-5, and 6-10 CPD, respectively, in men; 1.28 (1.01-1.62), 1.49 (1.34-1.66), and 1.68 (1.55-1.81) for 1-2, 3-5, and 6-10 CPD, respectively, in women. Similar associations were observed for smoking-related causes of death. Among former low-intensity smokers, younger age at cessation was associated with lower mortality risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: Smoking very low amounts was associated with increased mortality risks in Japan. All smokers should quit, even if they smoke very few cigarettes per day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoking and colorectal cancer: A pooled analysis of 10 population‐based cohort studies in Japan</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/smkcolocan_pool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/smkcolocan_pool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smoking has been consistently associated with the risk of colorectal cancer (CRC) in Western populations; however, evidence is limited and inconsistent in Asian people. To assess the association of smoking status, smoking intensity and smoking cessation with colorectal risk in the Japanese population, we performed a pooled analysis of 10 population‐based cohort studies. Study‐specific hazard ratios (HRs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were estimated using Cox&amp;rsquo;s proportional hazards model and then pooled using a random‐effects model. Among 363409 participants followed up for 2666004 person‐years, 9232 incident CRCs were identified. In men, compared with never smokers, ever smokers showed higher risk of CRC. The HRs (95% CI) were 1.19 (1.10‐1.29) for CRC, 1.19 (1.09‐1.30) for colon cancer, 1.28 (1.13‐1.46) for distal colon cancer and 1.21 (1.07‐1.36) for rectal cancer. Smoking was associated with risk of CRC in a dose‐response manner. In women, compared with never smokers, ever smokers showed increased risk of distal colon cancer (1.47 [1.19‐1.82]). There was no evidence of a significant gender difference in the association of smoking and CRC risk. Our results confirm that smoking is associated with an increased risk of CRC, both overall and subsites, in Japanese men and distal colon cancer in Japanese women.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
