<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Manami Inoue | Chaochen Wang - Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/manami-inoue/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/manami-inoue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Manami Inoue</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2024 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Manami Inoue</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/manami-inoue/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burden of cancer attributable to infection in Japan in 2015</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2021infectionpaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2021infectionpaf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Population attributable fraction (PAF) offers a means to quantify cancer burden that is attributable to a specific etiological factor. To better characterize the current cancer burden due to infection in the Japanese population, we estimated the PAF for cancer incidence and mortality in 2015 that could be attributable to infectious agents, including Helicobacter pylori (&lt;em&gt;H. pylori&lt;/em&gt;), Hepatitis B and C (HBV/HCV), Human papillomavirus virus (HPV), Epstein-Barr virus, and human T-lymphotropic virus type 1. We estimated the PAFs for each infectious agent on the basis of representative data on prevalence and risk-outcome associations assuming a latency period of 10 years. Overall, 16.6% of cancer cases in 2015 in Japan were attributable to the infectious agents included in this analysis. The estimated PAF was slightly higher in men (18.1%) than in women (14.7%). The highest proportion of cancer deaths attributable to infectious agents was observed for H. pylori infection, followed by HBV/HCV, and HPV infection. Our findings corroborated with previous estimates that &lt;em&gt;H. pylori&lt;/em&gt; and HBV/HCV infections were the two most important infectious agents in the Japanese population. Strategies focusing on eradication of infectious agents among infected individuals or primary prevention through vaccination could decrease the burden of infection-related cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-intensity cigarette smoking and mortality risks: a pooled analysis of prospective cohort studies in Japan</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2021lowintensity_pool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2021lowintensity_pool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: Increasing proportions of smokers in Japan smoke less than 10 cigarettes per day (CPD). Yet, the health risks of low-intensity smoking in Asia are poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: We performed a pooled analysis of 410,294 adults from nine population-based prospective cohort studies participating in the Japan Cohort Consortium. Cigarette use data were collected at each study baseline in 1983-1994. Study specific hazard ratios (HRs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs) for all-cause and cause-specific mortality were calculated using multivariable-adjusted Cox regression by CPD among current smokers and by age at cessation among former smokers with never smokers as the referent group. Pooled HRs and CIs were computed using a random effect model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: The smoking prevalence was 54.5% in men and 7.4% in women. About 15.5% of male and 50.4% of female current smokers smoked 1-10 CPD (low-intensity). Both male and female low-intensity smokers had higher all-cause mortality risks than never smokers. Risks were further higher with increasing CPD in a dose-response manner. HRs (95% CIs) were 1.27 (0.97-1.66), 1.45 (1.33-1.59), and 1.49 (1.38-1.62) for 1-2, 3-5, and 6-10 CPD, respectively, in men; 1.28 (1.01-1.62), 1.49 (1.34-1.66), and 1.68 (1.55-1.81) for 1-2, 3-5, and 6-10 CPD, respectively, in women. Similar associations were observed for smoking-related causes of death. Among former low-intensity smokers, younger age at cessation was associated with lower mortality risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: Smoking very low amounts was associated with increased mortality risks in Japan. All smokers should quit, even if they smoke very few cigarettes per day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoking and colorectal cancer: A pooled analysis of 10 population‐based cohort studies in Japan</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/smkcolocan_pool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/smkcolocan_pool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smoking has been consistently associated with the risk of colorectal cancer (CRC) in Western populations; however, evidence is limited and inconsistent in Asian people. To assess the association of smoking status, smoking intensity and smoking cessation with colorectal risk in the Japanese population, we performed a pooled analysis of 10 population‐based cohort studies. Study‐specific hazard ratios (HRs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were estimated using Cox&amp;rsquo;s proportional hazards model and then pooled using a random‐effects model. Among 363409 participants followed up for 2666004 person‐years, 9232 incident CRCs were identified. In men, compared with never smokers, ever smokers showed higher risk of CRC. The HRs (95% CI) were 1.19 (1.10‐1.29) for CRC, 1.19 (1.09‐1.30) for colon cancer, 1.28 (1.13‐1.46) for distal colon cancer and 1.21 (1.07‐1.36) for rectal cancer. Smoking was associated with risk of CRC in a dose‐response manner. In women, compared with never smokers, ever smokers showed increased risk of distal colon cancer (1.47 [1.19‐1.82]). There was no evidence of a significant gender difference in the association of smoking and CRC risk. Our results confirm that smoking is associated with an increased risk of CRC, both overall and subsites, in Japanese men and distal colon cancer in Japanese women.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing trends in the prevalence of H. pylori infection in Japan (1908-2003): a systematic review and meta-regression analysis of 170,752 individuals</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/hpylorimeta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/hpylorimeta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing trends in the prevalence of H. pylori infection in the general population over time are thought to be the main driving force behind the declining gastric cancer mortality in Japan. However, whether the prevalence of H. pylori infection itself shows a birth-cohort pattern needs to be corroborated. We performed a systematic review of studies that reported the prevalence of H. pylori infection among Japanese individuals. Meta-regression was conducted in the framework of a generalized additive mixed model (GAMM) to account for heterogeneity in the prevalence of H. pylori infection as a function of birth year. The prevalence of H. pylori infection confirmed a clear birth cohort pattern: the predicted prevalence (%, 95% CI) was 60.9 (56.3-65.4), 65.9 (63.9-67.9), 67.4 (66.0-68.7), 64.1 (63.1-65.1), 59.1 (58.2-60.0), 49.1 (49.0-49.2), 34.9 (34.0-35.8), 24.6 (23.5-25.8), 15.6 (14.0-17.3), and 6.6 (4.8-8.9) among those who were born in the year 1910, 1920, 1930, 1940, 1950, 1960, 1970, 1980, 1990, and 2000, respectively. The present study demonstrated a clear birth-cohort pattern of H. pylori infection in the Japanese population. The decreased prevalence of H. pylori infection in successive generations should be weighed in future gastric cancer control programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;click-the-graph-to-see-the-interactive-version&#34;&gt;Click the graph to see the interactive version&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rpubs.com/winterwang/bubbleplot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wangcc.me/img/Hpylori.png&#34; alt=&#34;Click for interactive version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;summary-statistics-from-fitting-meta-regression-in-the-best-modelclick-to-see-the-tablehttprpubscomwinterwangtable3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rpubs.com/winterwang/table3&#34;&gt;Summary statistics from fitting meta-regression in the best model.(click to see the table)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;table-of-risk-of-bias-diagnosis-click-to-see-the-tablehttprpubscomwinterwangriskofbias&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rpubs.com/winterwang/riskofbias&#34;&gt;Table of risk of bias diagnosis. (click to see the table)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Esophageal cancer in high-risk areas of China: research progress and challenges</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/esophageal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/esophageal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;purpose&#34;&gt;PURPOSE:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extremely high incidence of esophageal cancer in certain rural areas of China has prompted significant intellectual curiosity and research efforts both in China and abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;METHODS:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We summarize the research progress over the past several decades in high-risk areas (Linxian, Cixian, Shexian, and Yanting) based on literature research and our field trip (2012-2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;RESULTS:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considerable progress in clarifying the environmental risk factors and pathogenesis of esophageal cancer in high-risk areas has been achieved over the past several decades. Epidemiologic evidence suggests that carcinogen exposure and nutritional deficiency, rather than smoking and drinking, may be the major risk factors for esophageal cancer in the Taihang Mountains region, where the incidence of esophageal cancer is among the highest in the world. Two genome-wide association studies have identified variants in PLCE1 at 10q23 that are significantly associated with esophageal cancer risk. Recent whole-exome studies have revealed a comprehensive mutation pattern, in which the C&amp;gt;T transition is the predominant mutation type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;CONCLUSIONS:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite extensive research, the main causative factors that contribute to esophageal cancer in high-risk areas have not yet been elucidated. Challenges in this research area include determining the causative role of nitrosamine, identifying other potential carcinogens, and conducting fruitful international collaborative studies based on a multidisciplinary approach. Increased international collaboration will contribute to a better understanding of the etiology of esophageal cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
