<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>60s science on Be ambitious</title>
    <link>https://winterwang.github.io/tags/60s-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 60s science on Be ambitious</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://winterwang.github.io/tags/60s-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>溫度，污染，和電費</title>
      <link>https://winterwang.github.io/post/2017-06-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://winterwang.github.io/post/2017-06-12/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2017-6-12 16:6 用时：23:04 正确率：93% 错词：19个 提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 You may have noticed your summertime electricity bills, when you are you&amp;rsquo;re cranking the A-C. A–C, they are more pricey than your wintertime payments. That&amp;rsquo;s because air-conditioning is an electricity hog. And when a whole city or your region turns down the thermostat, utilities have to meet that increased demand somehow. This is often when we turn on the oldest power plants or the dirtier power plants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>男人的魅力來自女人</title>
      <link>https://winterwang.github.io/post/2017-05-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://winterwang.github.io/post/2017-05-31/</guid>
      <description>昨日說到BBC新聞聽寫在滬江外語學習之死。於是去跟他們客服詢問了一下。得到如下答覆： 好吧，內容優化，就是潔淨咱們的大天朝局域網唄，正準備學習外語的小朋友們怎麼能看到BBC，VOA上面對偉大祖國的描述嘛。曾經一直認爲，學習外語是爲了增進與他國的交流，互通有無，如今卻深刻體會到學習外語的真實作用是瞭解真實的中國，瞭解那個我來自的地方。
最近新聞酸菜館也變成了只賣酸菜的館，内容優化那叫一個好！
今天的聽寫講的是刊登在進化心理學雜誌上的一篇論文。說有伴的男人更受歡迎。科學家認爲女生更青睞有伴的男人，特別是伴侶如果美豔如花魅力四射，即使他們本身長相一般。也許是因爲這些男人如果不能用外表吸引人，那一定是富有內涵，或者是富可敵國的。總之一句話，男人被另一個女人證明了自己的價值，那女性便可省去自己去試錯的時間和精力成本。
听写于：2017-5-31 11:24 用时：19:27 正确率：93% 错词：14个
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
It turns out the best-looking thing on a man , maybe may be a good-looking woman. Researchers report that women find a man they see with an attractive woman more desirable than unattached men. That&#39;s according to a study in the journal Evolutionary Psychology. Researchers had two groups of female college students rate photos of men .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>遺傳物質的橫向傳遞</title>
      <link>https://winterwang.github.io/post/2017-05-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://winterwang.github.io/post/2017-05-30/</guid>
      <description>今日要祭奠BBC新聞聽寫在滬江外語學習之死。 幾周未見，今日登錄滬江準備聽聽久違的BBC。結果發現節目已經被下架： 然後我點擊其他訂閱的節目，結果一大半都“被下架”。細看過去全是外語新聞類，政治類的節目。現在連外語學習也已經進入了莫談國是的狀態了嗎？ 可憐的孩子們今後還有什麼資源可以學習英語呢？
悲哀。
連馬里蘭的空氣新鮮不新鮮都已經被上升到乳滑不乳滑了。我等草民還是閉嘴爲上策。親愛的朋友們，你們今天都健身了嗎？一切都只是剛剛開始。
听写于：2017-5-30 11:34 用时：19:08 正确率：93% 错词：10个
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
You can thank your parents for your DNA. Because humans share genes through sexual reproduction, passing DNA from parent to child. It&amp;rsquo;s known as the &amp;ldquo; &amp;lsquo;vertical transfer&amp;ldquo; &amp;lsquo; of DNA. Now imagine if you could share just 1 one or 2 two bits of your DNA with an unrelated stranger, through a handshake, or other incidental contact .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>