<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BBC on Be ambitious</title>
    <link>/tags/bbc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BBC on Be ambitious</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/bbc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>绝知此事要躬行</title>
      <link>/post/dictation2017-03-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dictation2017-03-13/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2017-3-13 18:20 用时：24:46 正确率：94% 错词：14个
 提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 In the early part of the last century, speculation about ilfe life on Mars was more florid, particularly by the American astronaut astronomer Percival Lowell. Through his telescope in Arizona, Lowell convinced himself he saw swaths sways of vegetation come and go with the seasons. Of course, he didn&amp;rsquo;t. What he really saw was shifted were shifting areas of sand dunes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>布克獎</title>
      <link>/post/2017-1-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-1-5/</guid>
      <description>听写于：2017-1-5 9:35 用时：26:08 正确率：88% 错词：26个
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
But we start with a literary star , - Paul Beatty, the first American ever to win the coveted Man Booker Prize, which is worth of £50,000 and a place on the best-seller list. The Sellout is a comic novel which is also unusual for a Man Booker winner . - I laughed out loud reading it .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>企業的社會責任</title>
      <link>/post/2017-1-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-1-4/</guid>
      <description>听写于：2017-1-4 10:8 用时：19:19 正确率：91% 错词：17个
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
Open any company&amp;rsquo;s annual report and chances are , there will there&amp;rsquo;ll be something about corporate social responsibility. Because we don&amp;rsquo;t just expect the company companies we buy from to be profitable; we expect them to be good corporate citizens, too. , which might explains explain recent news reports that Amazon has quietly appointed a new director of social responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>蛻變</title>
      <link>/post/2017-1-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-1-3/</guid>
      <description>听写于：2017-1-3 11:52 用时：16:56 正确率：94% 错词：12个
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
The rate of Chinese urbanization urbanisation over the last few decades has been astonishing. In 1990, a quarter of China&amp;rsquo;s population lived in urban areas. By last year, over half lived in cities . and the rate isn&amp;rsquo;t slowing. The governments government&amp;rsquo;s building cities across the country, hoping to turn farmers into workers and consumers to drive economic growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>宗教與食品</title>
      <link>/post/2017-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-1-2/</guid>
      <description>听写于：2017-1-2 10:01 用时：21:24 正确率：93% 错词：14个
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
For many people, the Christmas season is the a time for merriment, for eating, for drinking, and for doing everything to excess. If you were you&amp;rsquo;re religious, it might seem to go against what this time of year is all about. , and certainly , there is there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of church leaders who rail against the commercialization commercialisation of Christmas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>望子成龍</title>
      <link>/post/2017-1-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-1-1/</guid>
      <description>听写于：2017-1-1 10:23 用时：14:03 正确率：93% 错词：16个
概述：许多父母都对自己的孩子寄予厚望，愿意把宝宝的小动作解读为过人的天赋，但是有多少望子女成龙凤的父母能如愿以偿呢？也要有点“舍得孩子才能套着狼”的精神吧。新年BBC第一弹，祝大家元气满满！
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
In 1996, Dominique Moceanu made headlines as the youngest-ever member of the US Women&amp;rsquo;s gymnastic Gymnastics team to win a gold medal at the Olympic Games. Her parents were from Romania and inspired by the popular Romanian gymnast Nadia Comăneci, they had high ambition ambitions for their daughter. My parents had it in their hearts that when they had their first child, I would be a gymnast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>蓬勃的生活 Life, Animated</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-31/</guid>
      <description>Documentary follows autistic boy obsessed with Disney
听写于：2016-12-31 10:44 用时：19:00 正确率：95% 错词：12个
概括：《蓬勃的生活》根据Ron Suskind同名小说改编，是一部穿插动画与真实影像的纪录片，体现了自闭症儿童的家庭在照顾特殊孩子上所遭遇的困难。Suskind的儿子Owen三岁时不再说话，Suskind夫妇和Owen两岁的弟弟一直在与自闭症作斗争，想要维系他们与Owen的感情，而此时Owen唯一的爱好就是迪士尼动画电影。
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
The documentary , Life, Animated illustrates the story not just with clips from the films, but also its own animation. And it travels from Owen&amp;rsquo;s childhood through adolescence into adulthood, and even moving from home. Director , Roger Ross Williams had already begun to film with the family before Ron&amp;rsquo;s book, which is also called Life, Animated, was published.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1型糖尿病患者减肥要小心</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-30/</guid>
      <description>听写于：2016-12-30 16:37 用时：21:04 正确率：95% 错词：13个
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
Really briefly, Khalida, what is Diabulimia? A Diabulimia is an umbrella term , where people with Type 1 Diabetes deliberately reduce or admit omit the insulin that they need to be taking relative to the sugars, the blood sugars that they have and to the carbohydrates that they are eating with the aim of keeping their weight down or losing weight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>夏威夷的天堂生活</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-29/</guid>
      <description>听写于：2016-12-29 10:51 用时：24:29 正确率：90% 错词：22个
影片《后裔》以度假胜地夏威夷为背景，讲述中年男子处理突如其来的家庭危机，乔治克鲁尼凭借该片获得第69届金球奖最佳男主角。
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
Hello, . As family drama , the Descendants collects at the box office. , Director Alexander Payne describes the power of putting George Clooney in a Hawaiian shirt. The Gotham city for zombies and batman White batmen, why Glasgows smiles better. ? A cult film in more than one sense, Martha Marcy May Marlene, Director/Writer Sean Durkin, on his drewlim-like dream-like study of a girl on the run from the a controlling sect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>跟蹤和騷擾</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-28/</guid>
      <description>听写于：2016-12-28 11:45 用时：22:35 正确率：88% 错词：31个
概述：跟踪与骚扰的区别，前者对受害人的精神伤害更大
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
Stalking steals lives. It stops people from having the normal life sort lifestyle that you and I would&amp;rsquo;ve expected. You can would expect, we could go to work, take your kids to school, go about back your, sort of, daily business. It&amp;rsquo;s usually a campaign by somebody who&amp;rsquo;s fix stated fixated and obsessive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>零是偶数还是奇数</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-27/</guid>
      <description>听写于：2016-12-27 22:40 用时：17:55 正确率：92% 错词：20个
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
But why did Mayor Bloomberg say &amp;ldquo; even numbers and zero&amp;ldquo; ? Was it necessary to single zero out? It seemed a little odd to us. So we talked to Dr James Grime of the Millennium Maths Project at Cambridge University in the UK. And he says that the a similar issue came up in France in the 1970s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>生物鍾</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-26/</guid>
      <description>听写于：2016-12-26 11:48 用时：20:02 正确率：91% 错词：16个
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
My guest today, Russell Foster, has the grand title of Professor of Circadian Neuroscience at Oxford University, which is the science speak way of saying he is he&amp;rsquo;s obsessed with clocks . - not the ticking type, but rather our biological clocks and the rhythm rhythms of life. More specifically, he studies the way light controls our internal clocks and circadian rhythms , and works to understand how light and dark affect our well-being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>東德情節</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-25/</guid>
      <description>听写于：2016-12-25 13:1 用时：24:53 正确率：88% 错词：23个
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
We&amp;rsquo;ve undertaken this trip to interrogate the phenomenon of ostalgie, a nostalgia for the old GDR , which gripped grips some in modern Germany as well as my traveling travelling companion. We are We&amp;rsquo;re on a the train now, heading pretty much directly to Zwickau. The poor little Trabbi&amp;rsquo;s finally died at its death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>天注定</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-22/</guid>
      <description>听写于：2016-12-22 11:40 用时：19:38 正确率：91% 错词：17个
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
A film from China now, A Touch Of Sin, subvert subverts expectations. Firstly , it&amp;rsquo;s largely set outside the big cities in bleak rural towns and villages, sometimes dominated by a vast industrial complex. Then the its subject is sudden acts of violence, sometimes of serial surreal almost Tarantino intensity . on the part of ordinary systems citizens variously horrified, tracked trapped or exploited in China&amp;rsquo;s relentless drive to economy economic success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>足球運動員掙多少錢?</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-21/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-21 11:56 用时：18:57 正确率：92% 错词：17个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 But first, how did it used use to be ? and how did we end up here? In 1973, journalist Hunter Davies was allowed into the inner sanctum of Tottenham Hotspur. Davies spent the a whole season with the team, training with them, visiting the players&amp;rsquo; homes , and witnessing the dressing room confrontations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>人民幣可靠麼?</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-20/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-20 11:55 用时：19:49 正确率：94% 错词：8个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Well , it&amp;rsquo;s been another tough week on global stock market. It&amp;rsquo;s markets - big falls again on Thursday, concerns of a over central bank policy in the US. , but also , as ever , the state of China&amp;rsquo;s economy. One question is being asked: &amp;ldquo; how stable is China&amp;rsquo;s currency nowadays? &amp;ldquo; For months, the challenges China&amp;rsquo;s been facing had have been a talking point, growth down, stock markets sliding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>總統的COI</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-19/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-19 12:00 用时：19:55 正确率：91% 错词：17个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 How is Donald Trump going to avoid damaging conflict conflicts of interest once he takes up his position as America&amp;rsquo;s next president? A planned press conference was scheduled for this week on the matteris . It&amp;rsquo;s now being canceledcancelled. Mr . Trump would only say via his tweeter Twitter feed that no new deal will deals would be done while he was he&amp;rsquo;s in the White House.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>兩百萬</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-18/</guid>
      <description>概述：从小我们就被教育要拾金不昧，但是现实生活中有便宜可占的时候，你会怎么做呢？澳大利亚有位“lucky dog”，把银行当钱包，自称“年轻无知，糊里糊涂”透支了2百万澳元。。。做人还是要诚实啊
Australian man spent $1.5m over two years due to bank glitch and somehow got away with it
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-18 16:17 用时：20:03 正确率：91% 错词：25个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Now , what would you do , if you realized realise that you could keep withdrawing money from the bank way beyond what you&amp;rsquo;ve actually naturally paid into your account? A young Australian , Luke Moore found himself in that position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>澤國江山入戰圖</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-17/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-17 12:07 用时：22:37 正确率：91% 错词：15个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
The senior Taliban are surprisingly mild-mannered, . They don&amp;rsquo;t seem to get angry or happy. They believe absolutely that what they are they&amp;rsquo;re doing is right. , but they are they&amp;rsquo;re often naive when it comes to the media. In some ways, Afghanistan is an easy patch. There are no spin doctors here. Afghan men themselves are extremely courteous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>輪回轉世</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-16/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-16 12:31 用时：28:24 正确率：90% 错词：23个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 For Buddhists, god&amp;rsquo;s waiting room is a stepping stone to another life. And to learn more about that, I&amp;rsquo;ve come here to the Amaravati Monastery in its peaceful rural setting , near the town of Berkhamsted , north of London. And I gain I&amp;rsquo;m going to meet the abbot , Ajahn Amaro. &amp;ldquo; Well, from the Buddhist perspective, the things thing that causes the most trouble for us, while we&amp;rsquo;ar we&amp;rsquo;re alive, or we&amp;rsquo;re dying , is a the habit that of what we all will call clinging or grasping attachment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>強奸不犯法 喪盡天良的摩洛哥法律</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-15/</guid>
      <description>摩洛哥刑法规定强奸犯与受害者结婚可免除刑责，16岁少女自杀一石激起千层浪. Morocco protest against rape-marriage law
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-15 12:8 用时：22:26 正确率：92% 错词：20个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Women&amp;rsquo;s right campaign is rights campaigners in Morocco , it have been demonstrated demonstrating in the capital Rabat against the country&amp;rsquo;s rape law laws which allows allow the rapist to marry his victim in order to avoid prosecution. The protesters have been outraged by the suicide of 16-year-old Amina Filali last week after she was severely beaten when she was forced to marry her rapist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>也門飢荒</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-14/</guid>
      <description>Yemen Starving
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-14 14:14 用时：16:00 正确率：92% 错词：16个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 But first , the UN has issued a stock stark warning that an increasing number of children in Yemen face death from hunger because of a the lack of international help. The Wolrd World Health Organisation says more than half of the country&amp;rsquo;s hospital hospitals are not functioning , due to the conflict that&amp;rsquo;s lasted more than 20 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troublemaker</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-13/</guid>
      <description>Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s Tiny &amp;lsquo;Troublemaker&amp;rsquo;
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-13 12:04 用时：23:33 正确率：92% 错词：16个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 We&amp;rsquo;ve been hearing from controversial campaigners who&amp;rsquo;ve been making waves across Europe. Today , we go to Ukraine and to Kiev , where clashes between government forces and opposition groups have been the at their most violence violent since the unrest began in November last year. 34-year-old Tetiana Chornovol is an anti-government activist who divides opinion across in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>人性與戰爭</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-12/</guid>
      <description>How soldiers deal with the job of killing
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-12 14:24 用时：20:19 正确率：89% 错词：22个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Ben says he wanted to kill, . But there are others who are very reluctant. In the Second World War, one of the combatants , S. L. A. Marshall observed that many didn&amp;rsquo;t shoot. He wrote a study , called Men Against Fire , in which he concluded that there was a reluctance to kill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>亂局中的伊斯坦布爾(Istanbul)</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-11/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-11 17:20 用时：22:26 正确率：94% 错词：14个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
Today, a fascinating insight into what it&amp;rsquo;s is like to live in Turkey at a time of political repression. The country is in turmoil at the moment. There&amp;rsquo;s been a state of emergency for nearly 6 six months since the attempted coup. According to official figures from the Ministry of Justice. , at least 93,000 people are under investigation for their elegy alleged links to the coup plotters and around 34,000 are facing charges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>默片《拿破侖》</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-10/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-10 用时：21:39 正确率：94% 错词：5个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
This week in London, the cinema event of the year - if not the century - has been a five and a half-hour five-and-a-half-hour screening of a film made almost 90 years ago. It is It&amp;rsquo;s Abel Gance&amp;rsquo;s Napoleon, . Digitally restored, once neglected. , it was shown last Sunday with a live performance by the Philharmonia Orchestra conducted by the composer , Carl Davis, who&amp;rsquo;s just turned 80 , and who paid for the restoration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>對話總統演講撰稿人</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-9/</guid>
      <description>Speech Writer to the President
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-9 12:29 用时：21:01 正确率：91% 错词：30个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 I think that speech writing is one of those professions where not everyone knows that it exists. So , could you please explain to us, Sarada, what the role of a speech writer is? Sure, . And I would I&amp;rsquo;d be interested to hear how it might be different for Tina and Kosovo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>不可能的故事</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-8/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-8 11:32 用时：14:48 正确率：95% 错词：8个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点
We start today with the unlikely story of how an American woman came to be working with truckers to combat human trafficking. Kendis Paris lives in Denver, Colorado with her Anglican priest husband and her their two children. She used to spend her days making bread and cheese, home with her the kids. But now she travels the country, training drivers to recognize recognise and report human trafficking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>撒謊</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-7/</guid>
      <description>概述：对朋友撒了一个谎，需要用更多的谎言来圆它。所以，朋友之间还是坦诚一点比较好。
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-7 10:33 用时：28:09 正确率：89% 错词：33个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 In 1976, my friend Glen decided to give up advertising to spend a year teaching English in the Sudan. On his returnreturning, he was supposed to be staying with his brother, but they had a rower row at Heathrow airport a few minutes after their his plane had landed. , and so Glen phoned and asked if he and his new New Zealander girlfriend, Virginia, could stop for a short while in our spare room in the council tower block where we lived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>老年性瞬間失憶</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-6/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-6 12:9 用时：20:40 正确率：94% 错词：7个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Several senior moments have featured in the news of over recent months. At the beginning of February, Ed Balls forgot the name of Bill Thomas, his business ally. A few weeks later, Green party leader Natalie Bennett had a terrible time remembering her party&amp;rsquo;s policies when she was interviewed by Nick Ferrari on LBC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>川普閉關鎖國</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-5/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-5 11:56 用时：18:03 正确率：87% 错词：27个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 The Trans-Pacific Partnership is dead, so says president elected President-elect Donald Trump. He is going to He&amp;rsquo;s gonna kill it off, he says, on his very first day in the White House in January. So is this the first step towards what Trump watches watchers fear , it&amp;rsquo;s is going to be a more protectionist America under his presidency?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>命運不是天注定</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-4/</guid>
      <description>HOW A TEAM OF &amp;lsquo;UNCLEAN CLEANERS&amp;rsquo; FOUGHT CASTE WITH CRICKET
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-4 17:29 用时：23:16 正确率：92% 错词：21个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Today&amp;rsquo;s story is from India. There, even though discriminating against people on grounds of their caste has been illegal for years. , people can still find themselves severely disadvantaged. Vimal Kumar is from one of the lowest class castes - the Chuhras. They are sometimes called &amp;ldquo; the untouchables&amp;ldquo; .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《大洋之光》</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-3/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-3 11:49 用时：23:21 正确率：91% 错词：21个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Let&amp;rsquo;s begin, though, with a break in the voice, just holding back the sobs . because this is a week when crying at the cinema is positively encouraged. Why? A new film, The Light Between Oceans is - it&amp;rsquo;s an adaptation of M. L. Stedman&amp;rsquo;s novel about a couple played by Michael Fassbender and Alicia Vikander.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>控制野豬新方法</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-2/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-2 12:37 用时：26:21 正确率：91% 错词：24个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt that there has to be some method of controlling the boar. I&amp;rsquo;ve got the ability here to inject boar from where when we were worm them and things like that , from about 6 six feet away. But then when I had, heard that there was a firm, who could actually dart the boar, I was interested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>時間的錯覺</title>
      <link>/post/2016-12-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-12-1/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-12-1 17:9 用时：21:30 正确率：90% 错词：23个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 &amp;rdquo; Time present and time past / Are both perhaps present in time future . / And time future contained in time past. / If all time is eternally present , / All time is unredeemable. &amp;ldquo; The opening lines of TS Eliot&amp;rsquo;s Burnt Norton, the first of his Four Quartets, were written in the 1930s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>救贖</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-30/</guid>
      <description>Trevor McDonald on Redemption
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-30 11:49 用时：18:14 正确率：91% 错词：27个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 There are many views about the concept of redemption. It&amp;rsquo;s generally defined as the action of saving or being saved from sin, error , or evil. We take this to mean that someone has committed an act which is sinfull sinful or evil. My guest today did nothing of the thoughtsort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>敘利亞難民危機</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-29/</guid>
      <description>Crisis in Syria
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-29 11:36 用时：20:43 正确率：92% 错词：15个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 In the past six months alone, the number of people living under siege in Syria has doubled to almost a million. In the a briefing to the Security Council, the UN head of aid , Stephen O&amp;rsquo;Brien also warned that conditions in eastern Aleppo have had gone from terrible to terrifying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>一春夢雨常飄瓦</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-28/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-28 12:3 用时：24:42 正确率：89% 错词：26个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Washington has again voiced concern about Beijing&amp;rsquo;s activities in the South China Sea. China is building airbases on the harbors and harbours on reclaimed land there . and has occupied areas which other nations in the region regard as theirs. This week, America&amp;rsquo;s top navy commanders naval commander in the Pacific warns warned that it could all lead to a dangerous arms race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>身份竊賊</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-27/</guid>
      <description>The Secret Fraudster in my Family
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-27 13:58 用时：25:37 正确率：88% 错词：33个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Today , we have we&amp;rsquo;ve an intriguing tale from Illinois in the US about a stolen identity, missing money , and the a most unlikely for allfraudster. Identity theft is increasingly common these dayssince . It&amp;rsquo;s when someone gets hold of your name and personal information , and uses them to take out a loan or a credit card and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>一弦一柱思華年</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-25/</guid>
      <description>Cultural Inclusion and Exclusion
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-25 16:1 用时：29:16 正确率：91% 错词：23个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Now, Pokémon Go, . In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of it, it&amp;rsquo;s it is a worldly wildly popular augmented reality game just take that&amp;rsquo;s taken the world by storm since it&amp;rsquo;s launched. I&amp;rsquo;ve persisted resisted playing so farand . I&amp;rsquo;m worried I might get hooked and ended end up spending hours of my life trying to chase after Pikachu or a Jigglypuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>空城澹月華</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-24/</guid>
      <description>Sir Edward Burnett Tylor
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-24 11:44 用时：28:56 正确率：90% 错词：22个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Like many English men Englishmen who suffered from tuberculosis in the 19th century, Sir Edward Burnett Tylor went abroad on medical advice, seeking the dryer drier air of warmer regions. Tylor came from a prosperous Quaker business family. , so he had the resources for a long trip. In 1855 , in his early 20s, he left for the New World .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>異口同聲</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-23/</guid>
      <description>雙胞胎一起講話有點瘮人&amp;hellip;..
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-23 11:53 用时：18:50 正确率：89% 错词：27个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Paula and Bridgette Powers are identical twins from eastern Australia who do the most extraordinary thing. They choose to speak at the same time. The pair has have spent almost every day of their lives together. They are in their 40s now . and they share a passion for seabirds. They set up the Twinnies Pelican and Seabird Rescue refuge off the Sunshine Coast .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>大草原上的農業</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-22/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-22 22:16 用时：26:49 正确率：95% 错词：12个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Last month, Global Trade Talks took place in Geneva. AlrightAll right, before you reach for your radio, please do not switch us off, . This is important. Governments were debating, yet again, whether it was time to cut the subsidies that some of them give to their farmers. It&amp;rsquo;s an old saw. Many, especially in the poor world, have been arguing against , since practiced this practice for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>另類保鏢</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-21/</guid>
      <description>(俄國人的口音真難懂(⊙o⊙))
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-21 11:56 用时：24:03 正确率：87% 错词：27个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 Today, an extraordinary insight into how things have been changing in Russia for gay and transgender people. At the end of the Soviet era in the 1980s, Tapir could wear high heels in the army and no one minded. These days he is he&amp;rsquo;s afraid for his life. Tapir identifies as gender quierqueer, somewhere between male and female.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>物換星移幾度秋</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-19/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
用时：24:13 正确：93% 奖励： 4 日期：2016-11-19
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 It&amp;rsquo;s that time of a year again. The Tuesday after the August bank holiday, summer holidays are almost over. Very soon, it would will be back to school. For those of us without children, the first clue is all the advertises for adverts of school uniforms. Getting kitted out for a new term is a lesson in life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>意大利地震成因</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-18/</guid>
      <description>Italy&amp;rsquo;s devastating earthquake
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-18 13:15 用时：28:52 正确率：94% 错词：15个
提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 I mean, it is that unfolding. It&amp;rsquo;s very unfamiliar to me. But you think these are all connected somehow. Well, first, earthquakes in Italy turn tend to occur more in groups or sequences than a lot of other places in the world. This is somewhat unique to Italy. It&amp;rsquo;s not a striking difference, but it&amp;rsquo;s a noticeable one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>地籟風聲急</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-17/</guid>
      <description>Fight for life by Sofia Zambuto
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-17 11:29 用时：21:51 正确率：94% 错词：18个
 提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 The silence was terrible. I knew it would hit us at any moment. When it came, the wave was colossal and came crashing crushing down on us. Two of my little ones clung to me. They saw their father go under. He disappeared. We didn&amp;rsquo;t see him resurface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>鐵馬冰河入夢來</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-16/</guid>
      <description>The Book that Changed Me Episode 5 of 5
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-16 14:46 用时：25:06 正确率：92% 错词：15个
 提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 The People&amp;rsquo;s War is a book of social history by Angus Calder. It was published in 1969 . and I bought it at Singapore airport when I was travelingtravelling, I suppose now I&amp;rsquo;d call it backpacking, in South East Southeast Asia. As I traveled travelled through Vietnam, where the American president said presence sat on the country like Goya Goya&amp;rsquo;s Colossus of Chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>唯一生還</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Miracle Girl&amp;rsquo;: Aircrash Sole Survivor
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-15 11:9 用时：24:33 正确率：94% 错词：16个
 提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 We are We&amp;rsquo;re starting with a remarkable survival story from the Indian Ocean. In June, 2009, a plane traveling travelling from Yemen to the Comoro Islands plunged into the water just a few miles from its destinationa reported crashed from . A report into the crash suggested that human error may have been one factor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>天價北京房</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-14/</guid>
      <description>Beijing&amp;rsquo;s Property Problem
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-14 13:50 用时：20:04 正确率：88% 错词：22个
 提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 The streets of Beijing are busy and bustling. China has undergone an economic miracle over the past quarter-century . and it&amp;rsquo;s in urbanization seen urbanisation on an unprecedented scale. More than half of the Chinese population now live in cities. The capital is home to 21 million people. That unofficial figure is almost double all the number who lived here of at the tenth turn of Milleniumthe millennium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>日以作夜</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-12/</guid>
      <description>Jacqueline Bisset
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 

听写于：2016-11-12 10:47 用时：27:26 正确率：88% 错词：25个
 提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 We are We&amp;rsquo;re beginning with one of the most popular and affections infectious examples of the Jone genre from 1963. 1973, because it&amp;rsquo;s there&amp;rsquo;s a new Blu-ray release of Francois Truffaut&amp;rsquo;s Day For Night, which takes it&amp;rsquo;s its title from the blue filter used to make daylight look nocturnal .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>歐盟加拿大籤署自由貿易協定</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-11/</guid>
      <description>Canada and EU sign free trade deal
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-11 16:48 用时：20:05 正确率：90% 错词：19个
 提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 After 7 seven years of negotiation and 7 seven days of at the bulging Belgian region of Wallonia digging that hills their heels in over approving the deal. , the European Union and Canada have finally signed that their landmark free trade agreement. After a short, but possibly in the circumstances, appropriate delay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>用愛治愈傷痛</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-10/</guid>
      <description>爲了準備IELTS雅思英語考試, 此篇文章之後的聽寫計劃盡量加入BBC英音的音頻資料.
Aleppo&amp;rsquo;s underground orphanage
Your browser does not support the audio element. 你的瀏覽器不支持音頻播放。請使用chrome科學上網。 
听写于：2016-11-10 15:38 用时：21:18 正确率：96% 错词：13个
 提示：红色：错误单词，绿色：补上正确单词，黄色：纠正大小写与标点 The rebel-held part of the city of Aleppo is currently under siege from Russian and Syrian government forces . and, according to the UN Special Envoy, faces total ruined ruin within the next two months. Before the war, Asmar Halabi ran two furniture shops in the city with his father, .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>