<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Masaaki Matsunaga | Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/masaaki-matsunaga/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/masaaki-matsunaga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Masaaki Matsunaga</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2020 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Masaaki Matsunaga</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/masaaki-matsunaga/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similarities and differences between coronary heart disease and stroke in the associations with cardiovascular risk factors: The Japan Collaborative Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccmatsunaga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccmatsunaga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background and aims&lt;/strong&gt; Coronary heart disease (CHD) and stroke have common risk factors, but some of these differ in the magnitude or direction of associations between CHD and stroke. We assessed whether the impact of each risk factor differed between CHD and stroke mortality in Asians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt; In total, 104,910 subjects aged 40–79 years without histories of cancer, CHD and stroke at baseline were followed between 1988 and 2009. Competing-risks analysis was used to test for differences in the associations of each risk factor with two endpoints (CHD and stroke). Population attributable fractions (PAFs) were also calculated for these endpoints to estimate the population impact of each risk factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt; During a median 19.1-year follow-up, 1554 died from CHD and 3163 from stroke. The association of hypertension with CHD was similar to that with stroke in terms of the magnitude and direction (multivariable-adjusted hazard ratio for CHD: 1.63 vs. stroke: 1.73 in men and 1.70 vs. 1.66 in women). Conversely, the magnitude of these associations differed for smoking (CHD: 1.95 vs. stroke: 1.23 in men and 2.45 vs. 1.35 in women) and diabetes (1.49 vs. 1.09 in men and 2.08 vs. 1.39 in women). The highest PAF for CHD was caused by smoking in men and by hypertension in women. That for stroke was caused by hypertension in both sexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt; Hypertension associations and PAFs were consistent between CHD and stroke, but not for other risk factors. These findings may be useful for optimizing public health intervention strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independent association of liver fat accumulation with insulin resistance.</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/liverfat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/liverfat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To examine the association of intrahepatic fat with homeostasis model assessment-insulin resistance (HOMA-IR), a marker of insulin resistance, in Japanese adults, and whether intrahepatic fat is associated with insulin resistance independent of waist circumference and other measures of obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifty-three individuals aged 37–69 were studied. Spectrum obtained using a 3-T magnetic resonance imager was analysed with LCModel to quantify intrahepatic fat. Blood levels of insulin, glucose and other biochemical markers were obtained after 8 h or more fasting. Percent body fat was estimated by a bioelectrical impedance analyzer. HOMA-IR and intrahepatic fat content were log-transformed in the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found a positive correlation between intrahepatic fat and HOMA-IR, which was independent of the anthropometric measures of obesity. In contrast, significant and positive correlations of body mass index, percent body fat, and waist circumference with HOMA-IR were largely explained by their associations with intrahepatic fat. Intrahepatic fat was positively associated with alanine transaminase and triglycerides even after adjustment for HOMA-IR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intrahepatic fat was associated with insulin resistance independent of age, sex, and measures of obesity in Japanese adults. Hypertriglyceridemia and liver injury may directly occur subsequent to intrahepatic fat accumulation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
