<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yingsong Lin | Chaochen Wang - Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/yingsong-lin/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/yingsong-lin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Yingsong Lin</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2021 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Yingsong Lin</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/yingsong-lin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk Intake and Stroke Mortality in the Japan Collaborative Cohort Study—A Bayesian Survival Analysis.</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccbayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccbayes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this study was to further examine the relationship between milk intake and stroke mortality among the Japanese population. We used data from the Japan Collaborative Cohort (JACC) Study (total number of participants = 110,585, age range: 40–79) to estimate the posterior acceleration factors (AF) as well as the hazard ratios (HR) comparing individuals with different milk intake frequencies against those who never consumed milk at the study baseline. These estimations were computed through a series of Bayesian survival models that employed a Markov Chain Monte Carlo simulation process. In total, 100,000 posterior samples were generated separately through four independent chains after model convergency was confirmed. Posterior probabilites that daily milk consumers had lower hazard or delayed mortality from strokes compared to non-consumers was 99.0% and 78.0% for men and women, respectively. Accordingly, the estimated posterior means of AF and HR for daily milk consumers were 0.88 (95% Credible Interval, CrI: 0.81, 0.96) and 0.80 (95% CrI: 0.69, 0.93) for men and 0.97 (95% CrI: 0.88, 1.10) and 0.95 (95% CrI: 0.80, 1.17) for women. In conclusion, data from the JACC study provided strong evidence that daily milk intake among Japanese men was associated with delayed and lower risk of mortality from stroke especially cerebral infarction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome-wide association meta-analysis identifies GP2 gene risk variants for pancreatic cancer</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/gwasgp2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/gwasgp2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer is the fourth leading cause of cancer-related deaths in Japan. To identify risk loci, we perform a meta-analysis of three genome-wide association studies comprising 2,039 pancreatic cancer patients and 32,592 controls in the Japanese population. Here, we identify 3 (13q12.2, 13q22.1, and 16p12.3) genome-wide significant loci ($P &amp;lt; 5.0 \times 10^{−8}$), of which 16p12.3 has not been reported in the Western population. The lead single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) at 16p12.3 is rs78193826 (odds ratio = 1.46, 95% confidence interval = 1.29-1.66, $P = 4.28 \times 10^{−9}$), an Asian-specific, nonsynonymous glycoprotein 2 (GP2) gene variant. Associations between selected GP2 gene variants and pancreatic cancer are replicated in 10,822 additional cases and controls of East Asian origin. Functional analyses using cell lines provide supporting evidence of the effect of rs78193826 on KRAS activity. These findings suggest that GP2 gene variants are probably associated with pancreatic cancer susceptibility in populations of East Asian ancestry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of the detection of Helicobacter pylori infection by commercially available serological testing kits and the 13C-urea breath test</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2019kawai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2019kawai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serum Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) antibody kits (LZ and LIA) using the latex agglutination immunoassay method are commercially available, but few studies have been performed to determine their diagnostic accuracy or to compare their results with those of enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) kits (EP and EIA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sera were obtained from 213 hospital outpatients with dyspeptic symptoms. The serological results were compared with the result of the 13C-urea breath test (UBT) which seems to be reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the 213 subjects, 154 were diagnosed as positive for H. pylori infection according to the UBT. The sensitivities and specificities of these tests were 97.4% and 76.3%, 98.1% and 78.0%, 99.4% and 74.6%, and 98.1% and 71.2% for the EP, LZ, EIA and LIA tests, respectively. When the 13 subjects whose seropositive results of the four kits were completely opposite to the negative results of the UBT were excluded, the specificities of evaluated kits were all higher than 90%. The concordance rate between the EP and EIA tests was 98.1% (Spearman&amp;rsquo;s rank correlation coefficient = 0.83) and that between the LZ and LIA tests was 97.1% (correlation coefficient = 0.91). The LZ gave higher antibody titer value than EP (p &amp;lt; 0.0001, Z = 9.82; Wilcoxon signed-rank test), and EIA gave higher value than LIA (p &amp;lt; 0.0001, Z = 6.43; Wilcoxon signed-rank test).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latex immunoassay method provided the same reliability to ELISA in terms of the diagnostic accuracy for current H. pylori infection, although we should take into account the titer value differences by each test method in practical use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction model for pancreatic cancer risk in the general Japanese population</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/predictionpancreaticgwas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/predictionpancreaticgwas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genome-wide association studies (GWASs) have identified many single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) that are significantly associated with pancreatic cancer susceptibility. We sought to replicate the associations of 61 GWAS-identified SNPs at 42 loci with pancreatic
cancer in Japanese and to develop a risk model for the identification of individuals at high risk for pancreatic cancer development in the general Japanese population. The model was based on data including directly determined or imputed SNP genotypes for 664 pancreatic cancer case and 664 age- and sex-matched control subjects. Stepwise logistic regression uncovered five GWAS-identified SNPs at five loci that also showed significant associations in our case-control cohort. These five SNPs were included in the risk model and also applied to calculation of the polygenic risk score (PRS). The area under the curve determined with the leave-one-out cross-validation method was 0.63 (95% confidence interval, 0.60–0.66) or 0.61 (0.58–0.64) for versions of the model that did or did not include cigarette smoking and family history of pancreatic cancer in addition to the five SNPs, respectively. Individuals in the lowest and highest quintiles for the PRS had odds ratios of 0.62 (0.42–0.91) and 1.98 (1.42–2.76), respectively, for pancreatic cancer development compared with those in the middle quintile. We have thus developed a risk model for pancreatic cancer that showed moderately good discriminatory ability with regard to differentiation of pancreatic cancer patients from control individuals. Our findings suggest the potential utility of a risk model that incorporates replicated GWAS-identified SNPs and established demographic or environmental factors for the identification of individuals at increased risk for pancreatic cancer development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing trends in the prevalence of H. pylori infection in Japan (1908-2003): a systematic review and meta-regression analysis of 170,752 individuals</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/hpylorimeta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/hpylorimeta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing trends in the prevalence of H. pylori infection in the general population over time are thought to be the main driving force behind the declining gastric cancer mortality in Japan. However, whether the prevalence of H. pylori infection itself shows a birth-cohort pattern needs to be corroborated. We performed a systematic review of studies that reported the prevalence of H. pylori infection among Japanese individuals. Meta-regression was conducted in the framework of a generalized additive mixed model (GAMM) to account for heterogeneity in the prevalence of H. pylori infection as a function of birth year. The prevalence of H. pylori infection confirmed a clear birth cohort pattern: the predicted prevalence (%, 95% CI) was 60.9 (56.3-65.4), 65.9 (63.9-67.9), 67.4 (66.0-68.7), 64.1 (63.1-65.1), 59.1 (58.2-60.0), 49.1 (49.0-49.2), 34.9 (34.0-35.8), 24.6 (23.5-25.8), 15.6 (14.0-17.3), and 6.6 (4.8-8.9) among those who were born in the year 1910, 1920, 1930, 1940, 1950, 1960, 1970, 1980, 1990, and 2000, respectively. The present study demonstrated a clear birth-cohort pattern of H. pylori infection in the Japanese population. The decreased prevalence of H. pylori infection in successive generations should be weighed in future gastric cancer control programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;click-the-graph-to-see-the-interactive-version&#34;&gt;Click the graph to see the interactive version&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rpubs.com/winterwang/bubbleplot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wangcc.me/img/Hpylori.png&#34; alt=&#34;Click for interactive version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;summary-statistics-from-fitting-meta-regression-in-the-best-modelclick-to-see-the-tablehttprpubscomwinterwangtable3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rpubs.com/winterwang/table3&#34;&gt;Summary statistics from fitting meta-regression in the best model.(click to see the table)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;table-of-risk-of-bias-diagnosis-click-to-see-the-tablehttprpubscomwinterwangriskofbias&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rpubs.com/winterwang/riskofbias&#34;&gt;Table of risk of bias diagnosis. (click to see the table)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceived Stress and Colorectal Cancer Incidence: The Japan Collaborative Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccstress_colorectal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccstress_colorectal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancer is the third most common cancer worldwide, and many risk factors for colorectal cancer have been established. However, it remains uncertain whether psychological stress contributes to the onset of colorectal cancer. Therefore, we conducted a large-scale prospective cohort study to confirm the association between perceived stress and colorectal cancer incidence. We identified 680 cases of colon cancer and 330 cases of rectal cancer during a maximum of 21-year follow-up of 61,563 Japanese men and women. Cox regression analysis adjusted for potential confounders revealed a significant association of perceived stress with rectal cancer incidence but not with colon cancer incidence. This finding is partly consistent with that from only one previous study that addressed an association between perceived stress and the risk of colorectal cancer. However, studies on this topic are sparse and warrant further exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Esophageal cancer in high-risk areas of China: research progress and challenges</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/esophageal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/esophageal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;purpose&#34;&gt;PURPOSE:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extremely high incidence of esophageal cancer in certain rural areas of China has prompted significant intellectual curiosity and research efforts both in China and abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;METHODS:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We summarize the research progress over the past several decades in high-risk areas (Linxian, Cixian, Shexian, and Yanting) based on literature research and our field trip (2012-2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;RESULTS:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considerable progress in clarifying the environmental risk factors and pathogenesis of esophageal cancer in high-risk areas has been achieved over the past several decades. Epidemiologic evidence suggests that carcinogen exposure and nutritional deficiency, rather than smoking and drinking, may be the major risk factors for esophageal cancer in the Taihang Mountains region, where the incidence of esophageal cancer is among the highest in the world. Two genome-wide association studies have identified variants in PLCE1 at 10q23 that are significantly associated with esophageal cancer risk. Recent whole-exome studies have revealed a comprehensive mutation pattern, in which the C&amp;gt;T transition is the predominant mutation type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;CONCLUSIONS:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite extensive research, the main causative factors that contribute to esophageal cancer in high-risk areas have not yet been elucidated. Challenges in this research area include determining the causative role of nitrosamine, identifying other potential carcinogens, and conducting fruitful international collaborative studies based on a multidisciplinary approach. Increased international collaboration will contribute to a better understanding of the etiology of esophageal cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influence of personality and perceived stress on the development of breast cancer: 20-year follow-up of 29,098 Japanese women</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccbreast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccbreast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breast cancer is the most common cancer in women. However, it remains unproven whether psychological factors have an influence on breast cancer incidence. In our earlier study, subjects possessing two personality traits, decisiveness and “ikigai” (a Japanese word meaning something that makes one’s life worth living), showed a significantly lower risk of developing breast cancer, although no psychological factors have been convincingly demonstrated to have an influence on breast cancer development in other studies. Therefore, we conducted this follow-up analysis to confirm the association between breast cancer incidence and psychological traits, using the final dataset of a large-scale prospective cohort study in Japan. We identified 209 cases of incident breast cancer out of a maximum 21-year follow-up of 29,098 Japanese women. Cox proportional hazard regression analysis, adjusted for the same potential confounders used in our previous study, did not reveal any significant relationships between breast cancer incidence and four psychological traits: having “ikigai”, decisiveness, ease of anger arousal, and perceived stress. Our finding is consistent with previous studies, and suggests that the psychological traits are unlikely to be an important risk factor for breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
