<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yoshihisa Hirakawa | Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/yoshihisa-hirakawa/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/yoshihisa-hirakawa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Yoshihisa Hirakawa</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2020 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Yoshihisa Hirakawa</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/yoshihisa-hirakawa/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descriptive Epidemiology of Hypertension and Its Association With Obesity: Based on the WHO STEPwise Approach to Surveillance in Palau</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/palau/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/palau/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of noncommunicable diseases is a serious health burden for Palau. This study described the prevalence of hypertension, and assessed its association with obesity. Surveys following the WHO STEPwise approach to surveillance were conducted in 2529 adults. Multivariate prevalence ratios (PR) of hypertension for body mass index (BMI) categories were calculated by logistic regression models using conditional standardization procedure. Age- and sex-specified analyses were performed. Overall prevalence of obesity and hypertension were 40.4% and 46.8%, respectively. Prevalence of hypertension was positively associated with BMI. However, overweight men had as high prevalence of hypertension as the obese (multivariable-adjusted PR was 1.84 for overweight and 1.91 for obese compared with nonoverweight). The association between hypertension and BMI was similar across age groups. The prevalence of hypertension in women increased gradually with the increase of BMI whereas that in men reached a plateau already in the overweight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wangcc.me/img/Palaustudy.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevalence and predictors of prediabetes and diabetes among adults in Palau: population-based national STEPS survey</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/steppalau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/steppalau/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aimed to investigate the prevalence and predictors of diabetes and prediabetes among adults in Palau. We used data of 1915 adults, aged 25 to 64 years, who participated in the World Health Organization’s (WHO) STEPwise Approach to Risk Factor Surveillance (STEPS) study in Palau. Information on behavioral risk factors of NCDs and physical and biochemical measurements were obtained using standard methods of the WHO. The diagnosis of diabetes and prediabetes was based on the recent American Diabetes Association criteria. Predictors of the prevalence of diabetes and prediabetes were identified using multinomial logistic regression analysis. The overall age-standardized prevalence of prediabetes and diabetes were 40.4% (43.6% for men, 37.4% for women) and 17.7% (18.6% for men, 17% for women), respectively. Old age, overall obesity (high BMI), central obesity (large waist circumference or waist-hip ratio), hypertension and hypertriglyceridemia were significant predictors of prediabetes and/or diabetes. Diabetes occurred at a younger age in “obese” individuals than that of their “non-obese” counterparts. We confirmed that prediabetes and diabetes are highly prevalent in Palau affecting 40% and 18% adults, respectively. Introducing public health interventions to reduce and prevent obesity as early as possible could prove useful to curb the problem.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association between parental history of diabetes and the incidence of type 2 diabetes mellitus differs according to the sex of the parent and offspring’s body weight: A finding from a Japanese worksite-based cohort study</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/fhdm2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/fhdm2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To investigate differences in the association of parental history of diabetes with the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in the offspring according to the sex of the parent and the offspring&amp;rsquo;s body weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A prospective cohort study of 4446 middle-aged non-diabetic Japanese men and women were followed in Aichi Prefecture, central Japan, from 2002 to 2011. Subjects were categorized by their self-reported parental history of diabetes (&amp;ldquo;no parental history,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;father only,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;mother only,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;both&amp;rdquo;). The association of parental history of diabetes and incidence in the offspring was examined according to overweight status adjusted for age, sex, birth weight, smoking, alcohol consumption, physical activity, total energy intake, body mass index, and number of metabolic syndrome components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During follow-up (median 8.9 years), 277 subjects developed T2DM. Parental history of diabetes was positively associated with T2DM incidence. However, stratified analysis by overweight status revealed that only maternal history was associated with increased T2DM incidence in non-overweight subjects (hazard ratio=2.35, 95% confidence interval: 1.41-3.91). While in overweight subjects, paternal history was significantly associated with higher T2DM incidence (hazard ratio=1.98, 95% confidence interval: 1.19-3.28).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results suggest that parental history of diabetes mellitus is associated with the incidence of T2DM in offspring differently according to the sex of the affected parent and the offspring&amp;rsquo;s body weight.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
