<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Akiko Tamakoshi | Chaochen Wang - Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/akiko-tamakoshi/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/akiko-tamakoshi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Akiko Tamakoshi</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2022 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Akiko Tamakoshi</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/akiko-tamakoshi/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-intensity cigarette smoking and mortality risks: a pooled analysis of prospective cohort studies in Japan</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2021lowintensity_pool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2021lowintensity_pool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: Increasing proportions of smokers in Japan smoke less than 10 cigarettes per day (CPD). Yet, the health risks of low-intensity smoking in Asia are poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: We performed a pooled analysis of 410,294 adults from nine population-based prospective cohort studies participating in the Japan Cohort Consortium. Cigarette use data were collected at each study baseline in 1983-1994. Study specific hazard ratios (HRs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs) for all-cause and cause-specific mortality were calculated using multivariable-adjusted Cox regression by CPD among current smokers and by age at cessation among former smokers with never smokers as the referent group. Pooled HRs and CIs were computed using a random effect model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: The smoking prevalence was 54.5% in men and 7.4% in women. About 15.5% of male and 50.4% of female current smokers smoked 1-10 CPD (low-intensity). Both male and female low-intensity smokers had higher all-cause mortality risks than never smokers. Risks were further higher with increasing CPD in a dose-response manner. HRs (95% CIs) were 1.27 (0.97-1.66), 1.45 (1.33-1.59), and 1.49 (1.38-1.62) for 1-2, 3-5, and 6-10 CPD, respectively, in men; 1.28 (1.01-1.62), 1.49 (1.34-1.66), and 1.68 (1.55-1.81) for 1-2, 3-5, and 6-10 CPD, respectively, in women. Similar associations were observed for smoking-related causes of death. Among former low-intensity smokers, younger age at cessation was associated with lower mortality risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: Smoking very low amounts was associated with increased mortality risks in Japan. All smokers should quit, even if they smoke very few cigarettes per day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk Intake and Stroke Mortality in the Japan Collaborative Cohort Study—A Bayesian Survival Analysis.</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccbayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccbayes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this study was to further examine the relationship between milk intake and stroke mortality among the Japanese population. We used data from the Japan Collaborative Cohort (JACC) Study (total number of participants = 110,585, age range: 40–79) to estimate the posterior acceleration factors (AF) as well as the hazard ratios (HR) comparing individuals with different milk intake frequencies against those who never consumed milk at the study baseline. These estimations were computed through a series of Bayesian survival models that employed a Markov Chain Monte Carlo simulation process. In total, 100,000 posterior samples were generated separately through four independent chains after model convergency was confirmed. Posterior probabilites that daily milk consumers had lower hazard or delayed mortality from strokes compared to non-consumers was 99.0% and 78.0% for men and women, respectively. Accordingly, the estimated posterior means of AF and HR for daily milk consumers were 0.88 (95% Credible Interval, CrI: 0.81, 0.96) and 0.80 (95% CrI: 0.69, 0.93) for men and 0.97 (95% CrI: 0.88, 1.10) and 0.95 (95% CrI: 0.80, 1.17) for women. In conclusion, data from the JACC study provided strong evidence that daily milk intake among Japanese men was associated with delayed and lower risk of mortality from stroke especially cerebral infarction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoking and colorectal cancer: A pooled analysis of 10 population‐based cohort studies in Japan</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/smkcolocan_pool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/smkcolocan_pool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smoking has been consistently associated with the risk of colorectal cancer (CRC) in Western populations; however, evidence is limited and inconsistent in Asian people. To assess the association of smoking status, smoking intensity and smoking cessation with colorectal risk in the Japanese population, we performed a pooled analysis of 10 population‐based cohort studies. Study‐specific hazard ratios (HRs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were estimated using Cox&amp;rsquo;s proportional hazards model and then pooled using a random‐effects model. Among 363409 participants followed up for 2666004 person‐years, 9232 incident CRCs were identified. In men, compared with never smokers, ever smokers showed higher risk of CRC. The HRs (95% CI) were 1.19 (1.10‐1.29) for CRC, 1.19 (1.09‐1.30) for colon cancer, 1.28 (1.13‐1.46) for distal colon cancer and 1.21 (1.07‐1.36) for rectal cancer. Smoking was associated with risk of CRC in a dose‐response manner. In women, compared with never smokers, ever smokers showed increased risk of distal colon cancer (1.47 [1.19‐1.82]). There was no evidence of a significant gender difference in the association of smoking and CRC risk. Our results confirm that smoking is associated with an increased risk of CRC, both overall and subsites, in Japanese men and distal colon cancer in Japanese women.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similarities and differences between coronary heart disease and stroke in the associations with cardiovascular risk factors: The Japan Collaborative Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccmatsunaga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccmatsunaga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background and aims&lt;/strong&gt; Coronary heart disease (CHD) and stroke have common risk factors, but some of these differ in the magnitude or direction of associations between CHD and stroke. We assessed whether the impact of each risk factor differed between CHD and stroke mortality in Asians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt; In total, 104,910 subjects aged 40–79 years without histories of cancer, CHD and stroke at baseline were followed between 1988 and 2009. Competing-risks analysis was used to test for differences in the associations of each risk factor with two endpoints (CHD and stroke). Population attributable fractions (PAFs) were also calculated for these endpoints to estimate the population impact of each risk factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt; During a median 19.1-year follow-up, 1554 died from CHD and 3163 from stroke. The association of hypertension with CHD was similar to that with stroke in terms of the magnitude and direction (multivariable-adjusted hazard ratio for CHD: 1.63 vs. stroke: 1.73 in men and 1.70 vs. 1.66 in women). Conversely, the magnitude of these associations differed for smoking (CHD: 1.95 vs. stroke: 1.23 in men and 2.45 vs. 1.35 in women) and diabetes (1.49 vs. 1.09 in men and 2.08 vs. 1.39 in women). The highest PAF for CHD was caused by smoking in men and by hypertension in women. That for stroke was caused by hypertension in both sexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt; Hypertension associations and PAFs were consistent between CHD and stroke, but not for other risk factors. These findings may be useful for optimizing public health intervention strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceived Stress and Colorectal Cancer Incidence: The Japan Collaborative Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccstress_colorectal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccstress_colorectal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancer is the third most common cancer worldwide, and many risk factors for colorectal cancer have been established. However, it remains uncertain whether psychological stress contributes to the onset of colorectal cancer. Therefore, we conducted a large-scale prospective cohort study to confirm the association between perceived stress and colorectal cancer incidence. We identified 680 cases of colon cancer and 330 cases of rectal cancer during a maximum of 21-year follow-up of 61,563 Japanese men and women. Cox regression analysis adjusted for potential confounders revealed a significant association of perceived stress with rectal cancer incidence but not with colon cancer incidence. This finding is partly consistent with that from only one previous study that addressed an association between perceived stress and the risk of colorectal cancer. However, studies on this topic are sparse and warrant further exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influence of personality and perceived stress on the development of breast cancer: 20-year follow-up of 29,098 Japanese women</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccbreast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccbreast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breast cancer is the most common cancer in women. However, it remains unproven whether psychological factors have an influence on breast cancer incidence. In our earlier study, subjects possessing two personality traits, decisiveness and “ikigai” (a Japanese word meaning something that makes one’s life worth living), showed a significantly lower risk of developing breast cancer, although no psychological factors have been convincingly demonstrated to have an influence on breast cancer development in other studies. Therefore, we conducted this follow-up analysis to confirm the association between breast cancer incidence and psychological traits, using the final dataset of a large-scale prospective cohort study in Japan. We identified 209 cases of incident breast cancer out of a maximum 21-year follow-up of 29,098 Japanese women. Cox proportional hazard regression analysis, adjusted for the same potential confounders used in our previous study, did not reveal any significant relationships between breast cancer incidence and four psychological traits: having “ikigai”, decisiveness, ease of anger arousal, and perceived stress. Our finding is consistent with previous studies, and suggests that the psychological traits are unlikely to be an important risk factor for breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospective study of seaweed consumption and thyroid cancer incidence in women: the Japan Collaborative Cohort Study.</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccseaweed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/jaccseaweed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excess intake of iodine is a suspected risk factor for thyroid cancer. Previous epidemiological research from Japan reported that daily intake of seaweed was associated with a four-fold higher risk in postmenopausal women, whereas others reported a null association. A major source of iodine intake in Japan is from edible seaweeds, and it is reported to be among the highest in the world. We examined the association between seaweed intake frequency and the risk of thyroid cancer in women in the Japan Collaborative Cohort Study followed from 1988 to 2009. Seaweed intake, together with other lifestyle-related information was collected using a self-administered questionnaire at baseline. Seaweed intake frequency was categorized as follows: 1–2 times/week or less, 3–4 times/week, and almost daily. Hazard ratios and the 95% confidence intervals of thyroid cancer incidence according to seaweed intake frequency were estimated using Cox proportional hazards regression. During 447 876 person-years of follow-up (n=35 687), 94 new cases of thyroid cancer were identified. The crude incidence rate was 20.9 per 100 000 person-years. The hazard ratio of thyroid cancer in women who consumed seaweed daily compared with women who ate it 1–2 times/week or less was 1.15 (95% confidence interval: 0.69–1.90, P for trend=0.59). Further analyses did not indicate any association between seaweed intake and the risk of thyroid cancer on statistically adjusting for potential confounding variables as well as on stratification by menopausal status. The present study did not find an association between seaweed intake and thyroid cancer incidence in premenopausal or in postmenopausal women.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
