<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yoshinori Tanizawa | Chaochen Wang - Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/yoshinori-tanizawa/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/yoshinori-tanizawa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Yoshinori Tanizawa</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2025 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Yoshinori Tanizawa</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/yoshinori-tanizawa/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment selection and influencing factors for chronic lymphocytic leukemia: a physician survey in Japan</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2024cllsurvey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2024cllsurvey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;: Chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) is a rare form of lymphoma in Japan. This study aimed to explore hematologists&amp;rsquo; motivations and considerations in making treatment decisions for CLL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;: Responses from hematologists treating CLL, obtained through an online survey, were descriptively analyzed. Subgroup analyses by preferred first-line (1L) treatment, years of clinical experience, and level of interest in CLL were conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;: Out of 107 hematologists surveyed, 82.2% identified Bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitors (BTKi) as their primary choice for 1L treatment; the reasons included established clinical evidence (61.4%) and oral administration convenience (56.8%). Key factors influencing 1L treatment selection among those favoring BTKi included the presence of 17p deletion, TP53 mutation, and patient&amp;rsquo;s fitness status. BTKi was favored by 92.6% of hematologists with &amp;lt; 10 years of clinical experience and by 78.8% with more experience. The main reasons for choosing BTKi included safety (50.0%) and tolerance (46.7%) among hematologists who stated they had a specific interest in CLL and the oral administration route (62.1%) among hematologists with lower interest. When BTKi was used as 1L therapy, venetoclax-based regimens were preferred for second-line treatment. The most common concern about BTKi was substantial out-of-pocket costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;: Although many Japanese hematologists select their treatment based on clinical evidence, variations exist in treatment strategies, possibly associated with hematologists&amp;rsquo; experience and interest in CLL. These findings underscore the importance of further promoting evidence-based treatments to ensure that all physicians can make informed decisions. Future research should explore additional factors that influence CLL treatment decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: Chronic lymphocytic leukemia; Online survey; Treatment selection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-world Evidence of Skin Disorder-related Events Management in Patients with Lung Cancer Prescribed the RELAY Regimen (Erlotinib Plus Ramucirumab) - A Retrospective Observational Study Using A Health Insurance Claims Database in Japan [Article in Japanese] 肺癌患者におけるRELAYレジメン(エルロチニブ&#43;ラムシルマブ)処方時の皮膚障害関連事象マネジメントの実態-日本のレセプトデータベースを用いた後ろ向き観察研究-</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2024relay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2024relay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract-要旨&#34;&gt;Abstract 要旨&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;背景：&lt;/strong&gt; RELAYレジメン（エルロチニブ＋ラムシルマブ）は，EGFR遺伝子変異陽性の切除不能な進行・再発非小細胞肺癌治療に用いられるが，皮膚障害の発現が懸念される。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;方法：&lt;/strong&gt; MDVデータベースを用いて，RELAYレジメン治療を受けた患者の特徴，テトラサイクリン系またはマクロライド系抗菌薬（以下，抗菌薬）の予防投与の有無，保湿薬やステロイド外用薬の処方状況を調査し，抗菌薬の予防投与の有無とRELAYレジメン開始後新たにレセプトに記録された皮膚障害関連事象との関連をロジスティック回帰モデルで分析した。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;結果：&lt;/strong&gt; 研究対象227名中，抗菌薬の予防投与群は67名（29.5％）で，主にテトラサイクリン系抗菌薬が処方されていた。予防投与群でRELAYレジメン開始前からの保湿薬の処方割合は高く，開始後新たに記録されたざ瘡様皮疹，皮膚乾燥，および皮膚炎の割合は低かった。保湿薬・ステロイド外用薬の有無等を因子に含む多変量モデルで，抗菌薬の予防投与なしに対する予防投与ありでのざ瘡様皮疹のオッズ比は有意に1を下回った。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;結論：&lt;/strong&gt; 抗菌薬の予防投与はRELAYレジメン治療に伴うざ瘡様皮疹の発現抑制に貢献すると考えられた。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background：&lt;/strong&gt; The RELAY regimen（erlotinib＋ramucirumab）is used for the　treatment of EGFR-mutated, unresectable, advanced or recurrent non-small cell lung　cancer；however, the onset of skin disorders is concerning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods：&lt;/strong&gt; Using the Medical Data Vision database, we described the characteristics　of patients treated with the RELAY regimen, including prior use of tetracycline or macrolide antibiotics, and the prescription status of moisturizing agents and topical steroids. Furthermore, we used logistic regression models to analyze the association between prior antibiotic use and skin disorder-related events newly recorded in health insurance claims after the start of the RELAY regimen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results：&lt;/strong&gt; Of 227 patients, 67 patients（29.5％）had received prior antibiotics, primarily tetracyclines. In patients with prior antibiotic use, the prescription rate of moisturizers before the start of the RELAY regimen was high, and the rates of newly recorded dermatitis acneiform, dry skin, and dermatitis after the start of the RELAY regimen were low. In a multivariate model that includes factors such as the presence or absence of moisturizers or topical steroids, the odds ratio of dermatitis acneiform with prior antibiotic use was significantly lower than 1 when no prior antibiotic use was set as the reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions：&lt;/strong&gt; Prior antibiotic use may contribute to the suppression of dermatitis acneiform in patients with lung cancer treated with the RELAY regimen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key words：&lt;/strong&gt; EGFR inhibitor, prior antibiotic use, non-small cell lung cancer, ramucirumab, health insurance claims database&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment patterns in patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia/small lymphocytic lymphoma post covalent Bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitor treatment: a Japanese claims database study</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/cllmdv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/cllmdv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard treatment has not been established for patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) or small lymphocytic lymphoma (SLL) after discontinuation of covalent Bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitor (cBTKi) therapy. This retrospective, administrative database (Medical Data Vision) study described the patient characteristics, treatment patterns, and factors associated with receiving post-first-cBTKi treatment in Japanese patients with CLL/SLL. Patients aged ≥18 years with confirmed CLL/SLL diagnosis and treated with anti-neoplastic drugs indicated for CLL/SLL between March 2013 and February 2022 were included. Patient characteristics at baseline (first line), first cBTKi exposure (first-cBTKi), post-first-cBTKi treatment received, and the treatment sequence of CLL drugs received first line through third line, were described. Time-to-event analyses used the Kaplan-Meier method. Multivariable logistic regression analysis was used to explore factors associated with receiving post-first-cBTKi treatment among patients who discontinued first-cBTKi treatment. Among 2,424 eligible patients (median age: 72.0 years, 61.9% male), 450 (18.6%) received cBTKi in any treatment line. Among patients treated with cBTKi, 273 (60.7%) discontinued treatment; 56.0% of them (n = 153/273) received subsequent treatment. Median duration of post-first-cBTKi treatment was 2.2 months (95% confidence interval [CI]: 1.8, 3.5). The most common regimens post-first-cBTKi were cBTKi therapy (47.7%), bendamustine-based therapy (17.0%), and venetoclax-based therapy (13.1%). Patients aged &amp;lt;75 years (odds ratio [OR] [95% CI]: 2.0 [1.2, 3.4]) and those who did not receive blood transfusion during cBTKi treatment (OR [95% CI]: 2.3 [1.3, 4.1]) were more likely to receive post-first-cBTKi treatment. In conclusion, Japanese patients with CLL/SLL received various treatments for short duration after first-cBTKi discontinuation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: cBTKi; chronic lymphocytic leukemia; small lymphocytic lymphoma; time to treatment discontinuation; treatment patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
