<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chifa Chiang | Chaochen Wang - Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/chifa-chiang/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/chifa-chiang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Chifa Chiang</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2022 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Chifa Chiang</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/chifa-chiang/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descriptive Epidemiology of Hypertension and Its Association With Obesity: Based on the WHO STEPwise Approach to Surveillance in Palau</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/palau/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/palau/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of noncommunicable diseases is a serious health burden for Palau. This study described the prevalence of hypertension, and assessed its association with obesity. Surveys following the WHO STEPwise approach to surveillance were conducted in 2529 adults. Multivariate prevalence ratios (PR) of hypertension for body mass index (BMI) categories were calculated by logistic regression models using conditional standardization procedure. Age- and sex-specified analyses were performed. Overall prevalence of obesity and hypertension were 40.4% and 46.8%, respectively. Prevalence of hypertension was positively associated with BMI. However, overweight men had as high prevalence of hypertension as the obese (multivariable-adjusted PR was 1.84 for overweight and 1.91 for obese compared with nonoverweight). The association between hypertension and BMI was similar across age groups. The prevalence of hypertension in women increased gradually with the increase of BMI whereas that in men reached a plateau already in the overweight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wangcc.me/img/Palaustudy.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevalence and predictors of prediabetes and diabetes among adults in Palau: population-based national STEPS survey</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/steppalau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/steppalau/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aimed to investigate the prevalence and predictors of diabetes and prediabetes among adults in Palau. We used data of 1915 adults, aged 25 to 64 years, who participated in the World Health Organization’s (WHO) STEPwise Approach to Risk Factor Surveillance (STEPS) study in Palau. Information on behavioral risk factors of NCDs and physical and biochemical measurements were obtained using standard methods of the WHO. The diagnosis of diabetes and prediabetes was based on the recent American Diabetes Association criteria. Predictors of the prevalence of diabetes and prediabetes were identified using multinomial logistic regression analysis. The overall age-standardized prevalence of prediabetes and diabetes were 40.4% (43.6% for men, 37.4% for women) and 17.7% (18.6% for men, 17% for women), respectively. Old age, overall obesity (high BMI), central obesity (large waist circumference or waist-hip ratio), hypertension and hypertriglyceridemia were significant predictors of prediabetes and/or diabetes. Diabetes occurred at a younger age in “obese” individuals than that of their “non-obese” counterparts. We confirmed that prediabetes and diabetes are highly prevalent in Palau affecting 40% and 18% adults, respectively. Introducing public health interventions to reduce and prevent obesity as early as possible could prove useful to curb the problem.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association between parental history of diabetes and the incidence of type 2 diabetes mellitus differs according to the sex of the parent and offspring’s body weight: A finding from a Japanese worksite-based cohort study</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/fhdm2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/fhdm2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To investigate differences in the association of parental history of diabetes with the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in the offspring according to the sex of the parent and the offspring&amp;rsquo;s body weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A prospective cohort study of 4446 middle-aged non-diabetic Japanese men and women were followed in Aichi Prefecture, central Japan, from 2002 to 2011. Subjects were categorized by their self-reported parental history of diabetes (&amp;ldquo;no parental history,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;father only,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;mother only,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;both&amp;rdquo;). The association of parental history of diabetes and incidence in the offspring was examined according to overweight status adjusted for age, sex, birth weight, smoking, alcohol consumption, physical activity, total energy intake, body mass index, and number of metabolic syndrome components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During follow-up (median 8.9 years), 277 subjects developed T2DM. Parental history of diabetes was positively associated with T2DM incidence. However, stratified analysis by overweight status revealed that only maternal history was associated with increased T2DM incidence in non-overweight subjects (hazard ratio=2.35, 95% confidence interval: 1.41-3.91). While in overweight subjects, paternal history was significantly associated with higher T2DM incidence (hazard ratio=1.98, 95% confidence interval: 1.19-3.28).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results suggest that parental history of diabetes mellitus is associated with the incidence of T2DM in offspring differently according to the sex of the affected parent and the offspring&amp;rsquo;s body weight.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Skipping is Positively Associated With Incidence of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus: Evidence From the Aichi Workers’ Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/bfskip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/bfskip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skipping breakfast has been suspected as a risk factor for type 2 diabetes (T2DM), but the associations are not entirely consistent across ethnicities or sexes, and the issue has not been adequately addressed in the Japanese population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We followed 4631 participants (3600 men and 1031 women) in a work-site cohort of participants aged 35–66 years in 2002 through 2011 for T2DM development. Frequency of eating breakfast was self-reported and was subsequently dichotomized to breakfast skippers, who eat breakfast 3–5 times/week or less, and to eaters. Cox proportional hazards models were used to adjust for potential confounding factors, including dietary factors, smoking and other lifestyles, body mass index (BMI), and fasting blood glucose (FBG) at baseline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During 8.9 years of follow-up, 285 T2DM cases (231 men and 54 women) developed. Compared to participants who reported eating breakfast every day, maximally-adjusted hazard ratios and 95% confidence intervals (CI) of those with the frequency of almost every day and 3–5, 1–2, and 0 days/week were: 1.06 (95% CI, 0.73–1.53), 2.07 (95% CI, 1.20–3.56), 1.37 (95% CI, 0.82–2.29), and 2.12 (95% CI, 1.19–3.76), respectively. In a dichotomized analysis, breakfast skipping was positively associated with T2DM incidence (maximally-adjusted hazard ratio 1.73; 95% CI, 1.24–2.42). The positive associations were found in both men and women, current and non-current smokers, normal weight and overweight (BMI ≥25 kg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;), and normal glycemic status and impaired fasting glycemic status (FBG 110 to &amp;lt;126 mg/dL) individuals at baseline (Ps for interaction all &amp;gt;0.05).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The present study in middle-aged Japanese men and women suggests that skipping breakfast may increase the risk of T2DM independent of lifestyles and baseline levels of BMI and FBG.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoking and Diabetes: Is the Association Mediated by Adiponectin, Leptin, or C-reactive Protein?</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/smmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/smmd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background:&lt;/strong&gt; Although the association between cigarette smoking and risk of type 2 diabetes is well established, its mechanisms are yet to be clarified. This study examined the possible mediating effects of adiponectin, leptin, and C-reactive protein (CRP) concentrations on the smoking-diabetes association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; Between 2002 and 2011, we followed 3338 Japanese workers, aged 35–66 years, who were enrolled in the second Aichi workers’ cohort study. We used multivariable-adjusted Cox regression models to determine the hazard ratios and respective 95% confidence intervals (CIs) of the association between smoking status and risk of diabetes. A multiple mediation model with bootstrapping was used to estimate the magnitude and the respective bias-corrected (BC) 95% CIs of the indirect effects of smoking on diabetes through the three biomarkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; Relative to never smokers, the risk of diabetes was significantly elevated in current (hazard ratio 1.75, 95% CI 1.25–2.46) and ex-smokers (hazard ratio 1.54, 95% CI 1.07–2.22). The indirect effects of smoking on diabetes through adiponectin levels were statistically significant among light (point estimate 0.033, BC 95% CI 0.005–0.082), moderate (point estimate 0.044, BC 95% CI 0.010–0.094), and heavy smokers (point estimate 0.054, BC 95% CI 0.013–0.113). In contrast, neither the indirect effects of smoking on diabetes through leptin nor CRP levels were significant, as the corresponding BC 95% CIs included zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt; In our analysis, adiponectin concentration appeared to partially mediate the effect of smoking on diabetes, while leptin and CRP levels did not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Trend in Overweight and Obesity and Its Association With Cardiovascular Disease Incidence</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/globalobesity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/globalobesity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the global prevalence of both the overweight and obese is on the rise, there are variations among regions or countries, and sexes. Approximately half or more than half of the population are overweight/obese defined as body mass index $\geqslant$ 25 $kg/m^2$in the Americas (61.1%), Europe (54.8%), and Eastern Mediterranean (46.0%) according to the World Health Organization, while a much lower prevalence is observed in Africa (26.9%), South-East Asia (13.7%), and the Western Pacific (25.4%). Females are more likely to be overweight/obese in the Eastern Mediterranean, Africa, South-East Asia and the majority of countries in the Americas and Western Pacific but not in the most of the countries in Europe. These region-sex-ethnicity differences in prevalence may be a clue to the causes of the obesity epidemic. Epidemiological studies done in the USA, Europe, and Asia found that higher BMI was significantly associated with increased incidence of coronary artery disease (CAD) and ischemic stroke, but the association with hemorrhagic stroke incidence was not always consistent. The association of BMI with CAD and ischemic stroke was generally independent of known mediators, which would indicate the importance of controlling or preventing overweight/obesity for the prevention of cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association between five dietary health metrics of the American Heart Association and results of health checkups in a cross-sectional study of Japanese workers.</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/uemuradietary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/uemuradietary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;要-約&#34;&gt;要 約&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;目的&#34;&gt;目的:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;アメリカ心臓協会(AHA)は、心血管疾患による死亡率を 10 年間で 20%減少させることを目標として、心血管健康度(AHA 指標)を 2010 年に定めた。本研究の目的は、日本人の一集団において、AHA 指標の中の食事・栄養素摂取に関する 5 項目と健診成績との関連を調べることである。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;方法および結果&#34;&gt;方法および結果:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2002 年に 35-66 歳の愛知県内自治体職員 3,446 人に、簡易型自記式食事歴法質問票を用いて食事調査を実施した。AHA 指標の中で食事・栄養素摂取に関して定められた野菜・果物、魚介類、食物繊維の豊富な全粒穀物、食塩、清涼飲料水の 5 項目の各摂取量に基づいて対象者を三群に分けた。野菜・果物、魚介類は摂取量の最も多い第 3 三分位、食塩、清涼飲料水は最も少ない第 1 三分位を「良好な摂取状況」とみなした。食物繊維の豊富な全粒穀物は玄米・胚芽米・麦・雑穀を「いつも食べる」を「良好な摂取状況」とみなした。これら 5 項目について「良好な摂取状況」の達成項目数別の人数(割合)は、0 項目が 537 人(15.6%)、1 項目が1,453 人(42.2%)、2 項目が 1,029 人(29.9%)、3 項目が 365 人(10.6%)、4 項目以上が 62 人(1.8%)であった。この 5 項目の三分位による摂取量と健診成績との関連性を、性、年齢、喫煙歴、1 週間の運動日数、肉体労働の有無、アルコール摂取量、食事・栄養素摂取項目を調整して検討した。その結果、野菜・果物摂取量は body mass index(BMI)と負の関連、魚介類摂取量は中性脂肪(TG)と負の関連、HDL コレステロール(HDLC)、血糖(PG)と正の関連、食塩摂取量は TG と有意な正の関連、清涼飲料水摂取量は BMI、拡張期血圧(DBP)、総コレステロール(TC)、LDL コレステロール、TG、PG と有意な正の関連を示した。しかし、BMI を調整すると、魚介類と TG、HDLC、PG 以外の上記関連は統計学的有意性が消失した。食物繊維の豊富な全粒穀物と検査値との間には有意な関連は認められなかった。食事・栄養素摂取に関する指標の達成項目数と検査値との関連については、達成項目数が多い群ほど、BMI、TG が有意に低く、HDLCが有意に高くなる量・反応関係が認められたが、TG や HDLC との関連は BMI で調整すると有意性が消失した。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;結論&#34;&gt;結論:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本研究は一勤労者集団を対象としたものであるが、我が国においても、食事・栄養素摂取に関する AHA
指標と血圧及び脂質代謝異常との間に有意な関連がみられた。特に魚介類と清涼飲料水の摂取は複数の検査項目の異常と有意な関連を認めたが、そのうち清涼飲料水の摂取との関連は肥満を介することが示唆された。今後、我が国の生活習慣病予防対策を立案する際には、魚介類の摂取不足および清涼飲料水の摂取過多に関連する病態にも着目する必要があると考えられた。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;キーワードアメリカ心臓協会心血管疾患食事健診清涼飲料水魚介類&#34;&gt;キーワード:アメリカ心臓協会,心血管疾患,食事,健診,清涼飲料水,魚介類&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
