<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Takashi Matsuo | Chaochen Wang - Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/takashi-matsuo/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/takashi-matsuo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Takashi Matsuo</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2025 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Takashi Matsuo</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/takashi-matsuo/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patient and family burden in pediatric atopic dermatitis and its treatment pattern in Japan</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2024familyburdenpedatd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/2024familyburdenpedatd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background:&lt;/strong&gt; This study evaluated the level of burden in pediatric and adolescent atopic dermatitis (AD) patients in Japan, the associated burden on caregivers/families, and whether this burden varied with age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; Data were drawn from the Adelphi Pediatric AD Disease Specific Programme (DSP)™, a cross-sectional survey of physicians and their patients conducted in Japan between July and December 2022. Physicians reported patient demographics, clinical characteristics, disease burden, and current/previous therapies. Patients and/or caregivers reported perceived disease severity and impact of AD, including the Children&amp;rsquo;s Dermatology Life Quality Index (CDLQI) and Dermatitis Family Impact questionnaire (DFI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; Overall, 55 physicians provided data for 537 AD patients aged ≤17. Mean (SD) overall scores for CDLQI, POEM, and DFI were 9.3 (6.3), 8.3 (6.8), and 11.7 (7.2), respectively. Age was associated with higher patient and/or caregiver-reported CDLQI scores, which increased by 0.543 points per year of age (P = 0.01). Patients with severe disease reported a more significant impact on quality of life factors compared with mild patients (P &amp;lt; 0.001). Age was associated with higher caregiver-reported burden, with DFI scores increasing by 0.325 per year (P = 0.01). Physician-reported impact on caregivers showed that age was significantly associated with increased burden on sleep, daily activities, work, and mood (P &amp;lt; 0.05), with disease severity associated with impact across all factors (P &amp;lt; 0.01).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;: Both increasing age and disease severity were associated with the increased impact of AD on patients and their caregivers. Disease control/modification through appropriate therapeutic intervention at a younger age may relieve the burden of pediatric AD on patients and their families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: atopic dermatitis; caregivers; cross‐sectional study; dermatology; disease burden; pediatric; quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment persistence of interleukin-17 inhibitor class drugs among patients with psoriasis in Japan: a retrospective database study</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/il17trtsurvival/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/il17trtsurvival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background and objective&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-world evidence on persistence of interleukin-17 inhibitors (IL-17i) as a drug class among Japanese patients with psoriasis is lacking. Hence, we aimed to describe persistence rates of IL-17is among patients with psoriasis including psoriasis vulgaris (PsO), psoriatic arthritis (PsA), and generalized pustular psoriasis (GPP) or erythrodermic psoriasis (EP) in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: We analyzed claims data from the Medical Data Vision database. Patients ≥15 years old with a psoriasis diagnosis and an IL-17i prescription between November 2016 and August 2020 were included and followed through August 2021. Persistence rates of the IL-17i class among patients with psoriasis and its subtypes (PsO, PsA, and GPP or EP), and persistence rates of ixekizumab, secukinumab, or brodalumab among patients with PsO or PsA were analyzed using Kaplan-Meier method. Analyses were conducted in the bio-naïve and bio-experienced subgroups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;: The IL-17i class had &amp;gt;50% persistence rates up to 36 months among patients with psoriasis and its subtypes (PsO, PsA, and GPP or EP). 36-Month persistence rates for ixekizumab, secukinumab, and brodalumab were 46.2% to 57.7% in patients with PsO and 43.0% to 48.4% in patients with PsA. Across analyses, bio-naïve patients demonstrated similar or greater persistence rates than bio-experienced patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;: IL-17is&amp;rsquo; persistence rates over 36 months were &amp;gt;50% among patients with psoriasis and its subtypes (PsO, PsA, and GPP or EP) in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: IL-17 inhibitor; Psoriasis vulgaris; erythrodermic psoriasis; generalized pustular psoriasis; psoriatic arthritis; treatment persistence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
