<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wang, Chaochen | Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/wang-chaochen/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/wang-chaochen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Wang, Chaochen</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2019 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Wang, Chaochen</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/wang-chaochen/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid urine antibody test for Helicobacter pylori infection in adolescents</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/okuda/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/okuda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helicobacter pylori infection is associated with gastric cancer; thus, early diagnosis and treatment are crucial. Since &lt;em&gt;H. pylori&lt;/em&gt; infection in adolescents or young adults shows few symptoms, screening tests are necessary for this population. In this study, the accuracy of the rapid urine-&lt;em&gt;H. pylori&lt;/em&gt; antibody (u-HpAb) test was evaluated and compared to that of urine and serum &lt;em&gt;H. pylori&lt;/em&gt; enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays (u-HpELISA and s-HpELISA, respectively) in junior high school students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All 1,225 students attending the junior high schools in Sasayama city were invited to participate in this study. Urine and blood samples were assayed for anti-&lt;em&gt;H. pylori&lt;/em&gt; immunoglobulin G antibodies, and rapid u-HpAb was performed by three investigators independently. When the judgment of all investigators was in accordance, a positive or negative result was defined. Discrepant judgment was defined as an undetermined result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total, 187 students participated in this study and provided both urine and blood samples. Three students showed undetermined results with rapid u-HpAb. Excluding these results, the positivity rate of rapid u-HpAb was 3.3% (&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;184&lt;/sub&gt;), whereas that for u-HpELISA and s-HpELISA was 4.8% (&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;187&lt;/sub&gt;) and 5.9% (&lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;187&lt;/sub&gt;), respectively. Using s-HpELISA and u-HpELISA as the standards, the sensitivity, specificity, positive predictive value, and negative predictive value of rapid u-HpAb were 85.7%, 100%, 100%, and 99.4%, respectively when excluding the undetermined results of rapid u-HpAb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rapid urine-HpAb test had excellent specificity but relatively low sensitivity.
This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
