<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jenny Austin | Chaochen Wang - Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/jenny-austin/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/jenny-austin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Jenny Austin</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2025 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Jenny Austin</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/jenny-austin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Patient and Physician Disconnect on Satisfaction with Treatment for Atopic Dermatitis in Japan</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/adsatisfy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/adsatisfy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: Atopic dermatitis (AD) is an inflammatory disease causing severe skin itching. Data on patient-physician disconnect on treatment satisfaction in patients with AD in Japan are limited. We investigated patient-physician disconnect on treatment satisfaction in AD and if it influences treatment patterns, clinical characteristics, and patient-reported outcomes (PROs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Data were drawn from the Adelphi AD Disease Specific Programme (DSP), a real-world, point-in-time survey of physicians and patients with AD conducted in Japan from April to July 2019. Patients and physicians were grouped according to level of treatment satisfaction (&amp;ldquo;extremely satisfied&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;extremely dissatisfied&amp;rdquo;); with any level of dissatisfaction recorded as &amp;ldquo;less than satisfied.&amp;rdquo; Data were collected on treatment patterns, clinical characteristics, and PROs including the Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI), Patient-Oriented Eczema Measure (POEM), EQ-5D-3L questionnaire, and Work Productivity and Activity Impairment (WPAI) questionnaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;: Data were provided by 184 patients with AD and 56 physicians; 72.8% of patient-physician pairs reported a fair (kappa coefficient: 0.40) level of agreement on treatment satisfaction, 51.6% of patient-physician pairs were both satisfied, and 21.2% were both less than satisfied. Satisfied physicians prescribed a mean 1.2 fewer treatments than dissatisfied physicians (p &amp;lt; 0.05). Cases where both physician and patient were less than satisfied or where patients were less satisfied than their physicians reported the worst PROs, DLQI (both less than satisfied: mean 10.7 versus patient less satisfied than physician: 10.6 versus overall: 7.9), POEM (19.5 versus 17.3 versus 17.0), EQ-5D-3L (0.82 versus 0.81 versus 0.87) (all, p &amp;lt; 0.05). Work impairment was highest when both patient and physician were less than satisfied (p &amp;lt; 0.05). Physicians cited treatment efficacy and patients cited efficacy and usability as main reasons for dissatisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;: Overall, 12.0% of patients were less satisfied with their AD treatment than the physician, demonstrating some of the worst PROs, suggesting unmet need that could be improved by better patient-physician communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: Atopic dermatitis; Disconnect; Japan; Patient; Physician; Satisfaction; Therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
