<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Luigi Palla | Chaochen Wang - Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/luigi-palla/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/luigi-palla/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Luigi Palla</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2025 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Luigi Palla</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/luigi-palla/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relationships between food groups and eating time slots according to diabetes status in adults from the UK National Diet and Nutrition Survey (2008-2017)</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/ca_ndnsrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/ca_ndnsrp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time of eating has been shown to be associated with diabetes and obesity but little is known about less healthy foods and specific time of their intake over the 24 hours of the day. In this study, we aimed to identify potential relationships between foods and their eating time, and see whether these associations may vary by diabetes status. The National Diet and Nutrition Survey (NDNS) including 6802 adults (age &amp;gt;= 19 years old) collected 749,026 food recordings by a 4-day-diary. The contingency table cross-classifying 60 food groups with 7 pre-defined eating time slots (6-9am, 9am-12pm, 12-2pm, 2-5pm, 8-10pm, 10pm-6am) was analyzed by Correspondence Analysis (CA). CA biplots displaying the associations were generated for all adults and separately by diabetes status (self-reported, pre-diabetes, undiagnosed-diabetes, and non-diabetics) to visually explore the associations between food groups and time of eating across diabetes strata. For selected food groups, odds ratios (OR, 99% confidence intervals, CI) were derived of consuming unhealthy foods at evening/night (8 pm-6 am) vs. earlier time in the day, by logistic regression models with generalized estimating equations. The biplots suggested positive associations between evening/night and consumption of puddings, regular soft drinks, sugar confectioneries, chocolates, beers, ice cream, biscuits, and crisps for all adults in the UK. The OR (99% CIs) of consuming these foods at evening/night were respectively 1.43 (1.06, 1.94), 1.72 (1.44, 2.05), 1.84 (1.31, 2.59), 3.08 (2.62, 3.62), 7.26 (5.91, 8.92), 2.45 (1.84, 3.25), 1.90 (1.68, 2.16), 1.49 (1.22, 1.82) vs. earlier time in the day adjusted for age, sex, body mass index, and social-economic levels. Stratified biplots found that sweetened beverages, sugar-confectioneries appeared more strongly associated with evening/night among un-diagnosed diabetics. Foods consumed in the evening/night time tend to be highly processed, easily accessible, and rich in added sugar or saturated fat. Individuals with undiagnosed diabetes are more likely to consume unhealthy foods at night. Further longitudinal studies are required to ascertain the causal direction of the association between late-eating and diabetes status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/winterwang/TestReDOC/raw/master/Submit/Frontier/manuscript/Fig1_big.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day-Time Patterns of Carbohydrate Intake in Adults by Non-Parametric Multi-Level Latent Class Analysis—Results from the UK National Diet and Nutrition Survey (2008/09–2015/16)</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/ch_ndnsrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/ch_ndnsrp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aims at combining time and quantity of carbohydrate (CH) intake in the definition of eating patterns in UK adults and investigating the association of the derived patterns with type 2 diabetes (T2D). The National Diet and Nutrition Survey (NDNS) Rolling Program included 6155 adults in the UK. Time of the day was categorized into 7 pre-defined time slots: 6–9 am, 9–12 noon, 12–2 pm, 2–5 pm, 5–8 pm, 8–10 pm, and 10 pm–6 am. Responses for CH intake were categorized into: no energy intake, CH &amp;lt;50% or ≥50% of total energy. Non-parametric multilevel latent class analysis (MLCA) was applied to identify eating patterns of CH consumption across day-time, as a novel method accounting for the repeated measurements of intake over 3–4 days nested within individuals. Survey-designed multivariable regression was used to assess the associations of CH eating patterns with T2D. Three CH eating day patterns (low, high CH percentage and regular meal CH intake day) emerged from 24,483 observation days; based on which three classes of CH eaters were identified and characterized as: low (28.1%), moderate (28.8%) and high (43.1%) CH eaters. On average, low-CH eaters consumed the highest amount of total energy intake (7985.8 kJ) and had higher percentages of energy contributed by fat and alcohol, especially after 8 pm. Moderate-CH eaters consumed the lowest amount of total energy (7341.8 kJ) while they tended to have their meals later in the day. High-CH eaters consumed most of their carbohydrates and energy earlier in the day and within the time slots of 6–9 am, 12–2 pm and 5–8 pm, which correspond to traditional mealtimes. The high-CH eaters profile had the highest daily intake of CH and fiber and the lowest intake of protein and fat. Low-CH eaters had greater odds than high-CH eaters of having T2D in self-reported but not in previously undiagnosed diabetics. Further research using prospective longitudinal studies is warranted to ascertain the direction of causality in the association of CH patterns with type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wangcc.me/img/Figure3colored.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
The compositions (%) and absolute (kJ) energy consumption within each time slot by individual level carbohydrate eating classes: A, low carbohydrate eaters (LCE); B, moderate carbohydrate eaters (MCE); C, high carbohydrate eaters (HCE).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
