<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nobuo Kawazoe | Chaochen Wang - Be Ambitious</title>
    <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/nobuo-kawazoe/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangcc.me/authors/nobuo-kawazoe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Nobuo Kawazoe</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2023 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangcc.me/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Nobuo Kawazoe</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/authors/nobuo-kawazoe/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoking and Diabetes: Is the Association Mediated by Adiponectin, Leptin, or C-reactive Protein?</title>
      <link>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/smmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangcc.me/publication/journal-article/smmd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background:&lt;/strong&gt; Although the association between cigarette smoking and risk of type 2 diabetes is well established, its mechanisms are yet to be clarified. This study examined the possible mediating effects of adiponectin, leptin, and C-reactive protein (CRP) concentrations on the smoking-diabetes association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; Between 2002 and 2011, we followed 3338 Japanese workers, aged 35–66 years, who were enrolled in the second Aichi workers’ cohort study. We used multivariable-adjusted Cox regression models to determine the hazard ratios and respective 95% confidence intervals (CIs) of the association between smoking status and risk of diabetes. A multiple mediation model with bootstrapping was used to estimate the magnitude and the respective bias-corrected (BC) 95% CIs of the indirect effects of smoking on diabetes through the three biomarkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; Relative to never smokers, the risk of diabetes was significantly elevated in current (hazard ratio 1.75, 95% CI 1.25–2.46) and ex-smokers (hazard ratio 1.54, 95% CI 1.07–2.22). The indirect effects of smoking on diabetes through adiponectin levels were statistically significant among light (point estimate 0.033, BC 95% CI 0.005–0.082), moderate (point estimate 0.044, BC 95% CI 0.010–0.094), and heavy smokers (point estimate 0.054, BC 95% CI 0.013–0.113). In contrast, neither the indirect effects of smoking on diabetes through leptin nor CRP levels were significant, as the corresponding BC 95% CIs included zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt; In our analysis, adiponectin concentration appeared to partially mediate the effect of smoking on diabetes, while leptin and CRP levels did not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
